<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Bitcoin News Today - BeInCrypto</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-news/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 15:54:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/cropped-bic_favic-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Bitcoin News Today - BeInCrypto</title>
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-news/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>BlackRock Prioritizes Bitcoin, Ethereum, Delays Altcoin ETF Plans</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-declines-altcoin-etfs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum (ETH) News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana ETF]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=628128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BlackRock focuses on expanding its Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs, citing institutional demand and regulatory hurdles for altcoin ETFs like Solana and XRP.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-declines-altcoin-etfs/">BlackRock Prioritizes Bitcoin, Ethereum, Delays Altcoin ETF Plans</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>BlackRock, the world’s largest asset manager, has shifted its focus to Bitcoin and Ethereum, opting to bypass the launch of any new altcoin-based Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs).</strong></p>



<p>The firm&#8217;s Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH) ETFs, IBIT and ETHA, respectively, have shown significant performance milestones this year.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-stellar-performance-fuels-strategic-focus-for-blackrock-s-ibit-and-etha"><strong>Stellar Performance Fuels Strategic Focus for BlackRock’s IBIT and ETHA</strong></h2>



<p>Bloomberg ETF analyst Eric Balchunas reported the stance, citing Jay Jacobs, the head of BlackRock&#8217;s ETF department. He said that BlackRock does not plan to launch any new altcoin-focused ETFs. Jacobs also emphasized the company&#8217;s intention to concentrate on expanding the reach of its existing Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs, which have performed exceptionally well so far.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“We’re just at the tip of the iceberg with Bitcoin and especially Ethereum. Just a tiny fraction of our clients own IBIT and ETHA, so that’s what we’re focused on (vs. launching new altcoin ETFs),” Jay Jacobs reportedly <a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1867315163566629059" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The statement highlights BlackRock’s strategy to deepen its foothold in the cryptocurrency market through its flagship ETFs, as opposed to diversifying into smaller altcoins like Solana (SOL) or Ripple’s XRP.</p>



<p>Indeed, BlackRock’s Bitcoin ETF has been a standout performer, recently <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrocks-ibit-etf-europe-surpass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">surpassing over 50 European funds combined</a> in trading volume. Meanwhile, its Ethereum ETF <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-etha-billion-etf-club/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">joined the prestigious $1 billion ETF club</a> within just two months of launch. Taken together, these milestones display the increasing institutional appetite for these digital assets.</p>



<p>Against this backdrop, BlackRock’s success has been widely recognized. Its Bitcoin ETF was recently named the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-fidelity-bitcoin-etfs-top-performers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">top performer of the decade</a> alongside Fidelity’s FBTC.</p>



<p>These achievements align with BlackRock’s cautious approach to the broader crypto space. Earlier this year, the firm confirmed that it was not pursuing a Solana ETF despite market buzz. In late July, BlackRock’s digital asset head Robert Mitchnick cast further <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-no-immediate-solana-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">doubt on the immediate viability of Solana ETFs</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“I don’t think we’re going to see a long list of crypto ETFs. If you think of Bitcoin, today it represents about 55% of the market cap. Ethereum is at 18%. The next plausible investible asset is at, like, 3%. It’s just not close to being at that threshold or track record of maturity, liquidity, etc.,” Mitchnick <a href="https://www.theblock.co/post/307644/there-wont-be-a-long-list-of-crypto-etfs-blackrocks-robert-mitchnick-says" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, BlackRock’s skepticism on XRP ETF likely stems from the ongoing <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/ripple-vs-sec/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">regulatory uncertainty surrounding the token</a>. By focusing on Bitcoin and Ethereum, the asset manager appears to be doubling down on assets with proven resilience and market appeal.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-market-expectations-for-altcoin-etfs"><strong>Market Expectations for Altcoin ETFs</strong></h2>



<p>BlackRock’s cautious stance on altcoins aligns with its overall conservative investment philosophy, which is displayed in its <a href="https://beincrypto.com/vaneck-endorses-bitcoin-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hesitance to endorse a Bitcoin reserve</a>. Nevertheless, the firm has been vocal about Bitcoin&#8217;s role in institutional pockets, advocating for the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-bitcoin-portfolio-allocation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">allocation of up to 2% of portfolios to BTC</a>. This mirrors its confidence in the asset’s long-term potential.</p>



<p>Although BlackRock remains uninterested in launching altcoin ETFs, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trumps-win-influence-experts-weigh-in/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">analysts expect the US regulatory playing to change under Donald Trump</a>. Some predict that ETFs for assets like Solana and XRP could receive approval by the end of 2025.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“The greatest Solana win coming from the new Trump Presidency will be our long-awaited ETF in 2025 or 2026. No surprise, the incredible VanEck team will lead the charge here with support from 21Shares and Canary Capital,”&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/DanJablonski_/status/1854222437333811309" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>&nbsp;Dan Jablonski, head of growth at news and research firm Syndica.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>BlackRock’s potential shift toward entering altcoin-based markets likely depends on achieving regulatory clarity, which could drive significant demand. Meanwhile, Mike Venuto, co-founder of Tidal Financial Group, provided perspective on the broader ETF market, as noted by Balchunas.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“We have people coming to us all the time trying to pitch ‘Bitcoin + something else’ ETFs. Every options strategy you can think of is going to be tied to Bitcoin, Nvidia, Tesla, and MicroStrategy in ETFs. It’s coming,” Balchunas <a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1867316688880120175" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">reported</a>, citing Venuto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>BlackRock’s record-breaking success with its Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs underscores its strategic focus and alignment with market demand. While other firms explore altcoin ETFs, BlackRock’s dedication to expanding its existing offerings positions it as a leader in shaping the future of institutional crypto investments.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-declines-altcoin-etfs/">BlackRock Prioritizes Bitcoin, Ethereum, Delays Altcoin ETF Plans</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bic_Larry_Fink_Blackrock-covers_neutral_1.png" medium="image" width="1920" height="1081" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bic_Larry_Fink_Blackrock-covers_neutral_1.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Market Awaits Impact of Nearly $3 Billion Bitcoin and Ethereum Options Expiring Today</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/3-billion-in-bitcoin-ethereum-options-expire/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 05:48:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum (ETH) News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=627774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nearly $3 billion in Bitcoin and Ethereum options expire today, raising the stakes for potential price volatility. Will seasonal trends or inflation steer the market?</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/3-billion-in-bitcoin-ethereum-options-expire/">Market Awaits Impact of Nearly $3 Billion Bitcoin and Ethereum Options Expiring Today</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Friday is crypto options’ expiration day</strong>. <strong>Nearly $3 billion in Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH) contracts are poised to be settled or renewed today. Crypto markets have been climbing on the colloquial Trump rally over the past several weeks, but can they keep going?</strong></p>



<p>Expiring crypto options often leads to notable price&nbsp;volatility, prompting traders and investors to monitor today’s developments closely.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-2-72-billion-bitcoin-and-ethereum-options-expiring"><strong>$2.72 Billion Bitcoin and Ethereum Options Expiring</strong></h2>



<p>Deribit reports that 20,815 Bitcoin contracts, with a notional value of $2.077 billion, are set to expire today. The put-to-call ratio stands at 0.83, indicating that traders continue to sell more calls (long contracts) than puts (short contracts).</p>



<p>The maximum pain point (the price at which the asset will cause financial losses to the largest number of holders) is $98,000. Notably, this is a little lower than the current spot market price of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$99,758</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" width="1066" height="600" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-3.png" alt="Bitcoin Options Expiration" class="wp-image-627776" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-3.png 1066w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-3-360x203.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-3-850x478.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-3-768x432.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-3-150x84.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1066px) 100vw, 1066px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin Options Expiration. Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://metrics.deribit.com/options/BTC" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Deribit</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Meanwhile, 164,330 Ethereum options contracts, with a notional value of nearly $644 million, will also expire today. The put-to-call ratio is 0.68, indicating that, similar to Bitcoin, traders are selling more long contracts than short contracts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1072" height="588" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-4.png" alt="Expiring Ethereum Options" class="wp-image-627778" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-4.png 1072w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-4-360x197.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-4-850x466.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-4-768x421.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-4-150x82.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1072px) 100vw, 1072px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Expiring Ethereum Options. Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://metrics.deribit.com/options/ETH" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Deribit</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Greek’s Live commented that this week&#8217;s market was dominated by corrections, unlike last week&#8217;s, which was a smaller correction for Bitcoin and a stronger correction for the altcoins. However, with Christmas and annual delivery approaching, market makers are beginning to move positions.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“The recent Block call options trading accounted for a higher proportion, the daily average accounted for more than 30%. In previous years, the Christmas season in Europe and the US trading heat will be significantly reduced. This year, the influence of US stocks on the crypto rises, and this phenomenon may be more obvious,” Greeks Live <a href="https://x.com/GreeksLive/status/1867367492013916252" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This raises the question of whether there will be a Christmas rally this month, as the market has once again come to a position of stronger divergence. Currently, BTC is oscillating below $100,000, whereas ETH is oscillating just shy of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$4,000</a>.</p>



<p>The last two weeks of options market data have been showing that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/3-billion-bitcoin-ethereum-options-expiring/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">market makers are more cautious</a>. Amid sharp fluctuations in the market, there have been small rises in the main term implied <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-causes-bitcoins-volatility/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">volatility</a> (IV). Against this backdrop, analysts at Greeks.live say options are currently very suitable for short-term gaming.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“…the cost-effective way to buy options is still very high,” they added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, these expiring options come after a wild week from a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/protect-yourself-from-inflation-using-cryptocurrency/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">US economic data</a> perspective. US inflation rose to 2.7% in November, with core CPI remaining sticky at 0.3%. While a Fed rate cut is widely anticipated, stubborn <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/protect-yourself-from-inflation-using-cryptocurrency/">inflation</a> complicates the path for sustained monetary easing.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/3-billion-in-bitcoin-ethereum-options-expire/">Market Awaits Impact of Nearly $3 Billion Bitcoin and Ethereum Options Expiring Today</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BIC_Cryptography_Cryptocurrency_neutral_3.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BIC_Cryptography_Cryptocurrency_neutral_3.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlackRock Suggests Allocating Up to 2% of Portfolios to Bitcoin</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-bitcoin-portfolio-allocation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mohammad Shahid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 22:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=627609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BlackRock urges investors to allocate 1-2% of portfolios to Bitcoin as institutional inflows surge and the cryptocurrency hits $100,000.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-bitcoin-portfolio-allocation/">BlackRock Suggests Allocating Up to 2% of Portfolios to Bitcoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>In a recent report, BlackRock analysts suggested that Bitcoin should comprise 1% to 2% of traditional 60/40 investment portfolios.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>This marks a shift from mainstream investors&#8217; previous exclusion of the cryptocurrency.<br></p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-blackrock-s-bitcoin-etf-is-driving-institutional-adoption">BlackRock’s Bitcoin ETF is Driving Institutional Adoption</h2>



<p>BlackRock’s latest <a href="https://www.blackrock.com/institutions/en-zz/literature/whitepaper/bii-investment-perspectives-december-2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">report</a> offers guidance for investors willing to accept Bitcoin’s risks, outlining strategies for allocating to the cryptocurrency amidst its continued rise. </p>



<p>Factors such as President-elect Donald Trump’s supportive stance on crypto and his <a href="https://beincrypto.com/david-sacks-on-operation-choke-point/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pro-crypto nominations for key government roles</a> have fueled this year’s rally. Bitcoin’s recent $100,000 milestone was a psychological trigger for more institutional investors to engage with the largest cryptocurrency. </p>



<p>This was reflected in the ETF market, as Bitcoin ETFs, including <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrocks-bitcoin-etf-ibit-holdings/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT)</a>, have attracted billions in investments during this surge.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“New report from BlackRock today that  recommends 1-2% exposure to Bitcoin ETF, first time they gave specific number. They put this out because they had so much incoming on this question of how much?,” ETF analyst Eric Balchunas <a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1867204093594193975" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a> on X (formerly Twitter)</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Despite the gains, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/bitcoin-halving-history/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin’s history of volatility</a> remains a concern. BlackRock’s paper emphasizes a “risk budgeting” approach, urging investors to weigh potential rewards against inherent risks. </p>



<p>Bitcoin’s infamous price swings have led to drawdowns of up to 80% since its inception in 2009, even as it has surged 140% this year.</p>



<p>The cryptocurrency’s recent decoupling from traditional asset classes, such as technology stocks, is notable. BlackRock attributes this divergence to factors like increasing geopolitical tensions, global financial fragmentation, and eroding trust in banks.&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">The introduction of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-bitcoin-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">US spot Bitcoin ETFs</a> in January was a major catalyst for Bitcoin&#8217;s recent climb</span>. Assets under management in these funds have surpassed $113 billion, with nearly $10 billion invested since Trump’s election win in November. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="2307" height="584" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-84.png" alt="bitcoin etf weekly inflow" class="wp-image-627616" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-84.png 2307w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-84-360x91.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-84-850x215.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-84-768x194.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-84-1536x389.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-84-2048x518.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-84-150x38.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2307px) 100vw, 2307px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin ETFs Weekly Net Inflow. Source: <a href="https://sosovalue.com/assets/etf/Total_Crypto_Spot_ETF_Fund_Flow?page=usBTC" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SoSoValue</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Also, Weekly inflows remain extremely positive, with over <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-etfs-surge-as-liquidations-hit-billions/">$2.7 billion in the first week of December</a> alone. BlackRock’s IBIT leads these inflows, significantly outpacing competitors.</p>



<p>Combined, the 12 U.S. Bitcoin ETFs now hold more than 1.1 million BTC, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-bitcoin-etfs-surpass-satoshi-btc-holdings/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exceeding the estimated holdings of Bitcoin’s creator</a>, Satoshi Nakamoto. <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrocks-ibit-etf-europe-surpass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlackRock’s IBIT also holds higher assets under management</a> than all regional European ETFs combined.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-bitcoin-portfolio-allocation/">BlackRock Suggests Allocating Up to 2% of Portfolios to Bitcoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bic_Larry_Fink_Blackrock-covers_neutral_1.png" medium="image" width="1920" height="1081" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bic_Larry_Fink_Blackrock-covers_neutral_1.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Argentina&#8217;s President Plans To Embrace Bitcoin Payments in 2025  </title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/argentina-bitcoin-free-currency-circulation-president-milei/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mohammad Shahid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 20:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=627601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Argentina’s 2025 plans include free currency use, Bitcoin adoption, and major tax reforms, highlighting a shift toward financial freedom.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/argentina-bitcoin-free-currency-circulation-president-milei/">Argentina&#8217;s President Plans To Embrace Bitcoin Payments in 2025  </a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Argentine President Javier Milei has outlined key policy initiatives for 2025, emphasizing free currency circulation and pro-crypto regulation.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The new policies under consideration would allow Argentines to conduct transactions in any currency they prefer, including Bitcoin, driving financial freedom and flexibility across the nation.<br></p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-argentina-bitcoin-policies-to-follow-el-salvador-s-approach">Argentina Bitcoin Policies to Follow El Salvador’s Approach</h2>



<p>Milei also <a href="https://www.casarosada.gob.ar/slider-principal/50817-discurso-del-presidente-javier-milei-en-cadena-nacional-por-el-ano-de-gestion" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">announced</a> a sweeping tax reform aimed at reducing 90% of national taxes. This plan seeks to alleviate financial pressure on citizens and empower individual states to establish their own taxation systems, promoting localized economic decision-making.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“For a year now, there has been talk of free circulation, but it’s not true that there is real free competition between fiat currencies and Bitcoin. When you trade with dollars or euros, exchange rate differences with the peso are not subject to income tax, whereas with Bitcoin, they are. This significantly increases costs, deters and complicates the use of Bitcoin as a currency,” Ricardo Mihura, President of the ONG Bitcoin Argentina, told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In June 2024, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/javier-milei-bitcoin-currencies-free-competition-argentina/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Milei strongly advocated for Bitcoin adoption</a> and unrestricted currency competition in Argentina. While his vision echoed <a href="https://beincrypto.com/el-salvador-bitcoin-policy-imf-loan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">El Salvador’s early embrace of Bitcoin</a>, it remained tailored to Argentina’s unique economic landscape.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite criticism, Milei continues to champion cryptocurrency as a vital tool for economic transformation. Argentina has already made strides in <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/cryptocurrency-adoption-argentina/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">integrating crypto into its financial framework</a>. In 2023, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/argentina-paves-way-for-bitcoin-contracts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">government legalized contracts in Bitcoin</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With Milei’s leadership and his commitment to fintech freedom, cryptocurrencies could become more prominent in Argentina’s economy.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“I personally welcome the reduction of the State’s role in the economy. However, in the crypto economy, Government’s direct and indirect burden has increased and seems poised to continue growing. Regulations, agencies, and administrative obligations are being imposed solely to deepen the illusion of control that Bitcoin was designed to challenge,” Ricardo Mihura, President of the ONG Bitcoin Argentina, told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-south-america-s-crypto-momentum"><br>South America’s Crypto Momentum</h2>



<p>Argentina’s focus on cryptocurrency reflects broader adoption trends across South America. In Brazil, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/brazil-drex-cbdc-chainlink-microsoft/">Central Bank is responsible for the pilot project DREX</a>, the central bank digital currency (CBDC) platform. Global industry giants are involved in the Brazilian initiative, including Microsoft and Chainlink.</p>



<p>Also, Brazil leads in crypto ETF adoption, launching the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/brazil-solana-etf-launch-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first Solana ETF</a> and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-lists-ethereum-etf-in-brazil/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlackRock’s Ethereum ETF</a> on the B3 stock exchange earlier this year.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1067" height="635" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-83.png" alt="" class="wp-image-627602" style="aspect-ratio:1.6798418972332017;width:743px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-83.png 1067w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-83-360x214.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-83-850x506.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-83-768x457.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-83-150x89.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1067px) 100vw, 1067px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">South America Crypto Revenue Stats (In Billion). Source: <a href="https://www.statista.com/outlook/fmo/digital-assets/cryptocurrencies/south-america#revenue" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Statista</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Meanwhile, Venezuela has experienced significant growth in its cryptocurrency market. As BeInCrypto reported earlier, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/latam-crypto-news-october-12/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">market surged by 110% year-over-year</a> in Q2 2024, reaching $11.7 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This growth coincided with a rise in the value of the US dollar, positioning Venezuela as one of Latin America’s fastest-expanding crypto markets.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/latam-crypto-news-september-21/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rising momentum in South America</a> reflects the region’s potential to become a global leader in cryptocurrency adoption. Argentina is playing a pivotal role in the region under Milei’s forward-looking policies.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/argentina-bitcoin-free-currency-circulation-president-milei/">Argentina&#8217;s President Plans To Embrace Bitcoin Payments in 2025  </a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/bic_Javier_Milei_3-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/bic_Javier_Milei_3-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Texas State Representative Introduces Bill to Create Bitcoin Reserve</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/texas-bitcoin-reserve-capriglione/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Landon Manning]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 19:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=627584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Texas is considering a Bitcoin Reserve, aligning with a global trend to adopt crypto reserves. The legislation could rely on Texas’s mining hub status.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/texas-bitcoin-reserve-capriglione/">Texas State Representative Introduces Bill to Create Bitcoin Reserve</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>A State Representative in Texas just introduced legislation to establish a strategic Bitcoin Reserve. This bill is part of a growing trend to introduce similar reserves in several states and internationally.</strong></p>



<p>State Representative Giovanni Gapriglione suggests taxes, fees, and donations could fill this reserve but claims that Texas could purchase Bitcoin directly with enough political support.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-texas-bitcoin-reserve">A Texas Bitcoin Reserve</h2>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/12/texas-house-introduces-bill-to-establish-a-strategic-bitcoin-reserve.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CNBC</a> reports, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-regulation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">this pro-crypto legislation</a> would allow the State of Texas to build a Bitcoin Reserve. However, the bill does not include a proviso for direct BTC purchases by the state. </p>



<p>Instead, it would allow the state to receive taxes, fees, and donations in Bitcoin. <a href="https://beincrypto.com/missouri-texas-southern-us-bitcoin-mining-hotspot/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Texas is a major regional mining hub</a>, so several firms may be willing to make these payments.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;My goal is to make this bill as big and as broad as possible. This initial step is to allow some optionality and flexibility on it but if I am able to get support from other legislators, we will make it even stronger,&#8221; claimed Republican State Representative Giovanni Capriglione, who initially filed the bill. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Capriglione&#8217;s bill is inspired by <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trumps-speech-gensler-out-bitcoin-reserve-in/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">President-elect Trump&#8217;s stated plan</a> to establish a national Bitcoin Reserve. The largest cryptocurrency has rallied to new heights following his re-election, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-reaches-100k/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reaching the $100,000 milestone</a> earlier in December. Also, the US is already the largest BTC holder, which was accumulated from the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-government-will-sell-silk-road-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Silk Road seized funds</a>. </p>



<p>However, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-bitcoin-transfer-biden-trump-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">President Biden may begin selling off this existing BTC supply</a> during his lame-duck period. Notorious Bitcoin critic Peter Schiff <a href="https://beincrypto.com/peter-schiff-urges-biden-to-sell-us-government-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">encouraged this move</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="2582" height="1050" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-12.24.35-PM.png" alt="Bitcoin (BTC) Price Performance" class="wp-image-627587" style="aspect-ratio:2.459047619047619;width:924px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-12.24.35-PM.png 2582w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-12.24.35-PM-360x146.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-12.24.35-PM-850x346.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-12.24.35-PM-768x312.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-12.24.35-PM-1536x625.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-12.24.35-PM-2048x833.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-12.24.35-PM-150x61.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2582px) 100vw, 2582px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin (BTC) Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BeInCrypto</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Even if Trump&#8217;s plan to create a national Bitcoin Reserve is thwarted in the next month, several states are also pursuing independent initiatives. Florida&#8217;s Chief Financial Officer <a href="https://beincrypto.com/florida-states-cfo-endorses-bitcoin-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">proposed another state-level reserve in October</a>, and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/pennsylvania-proposes-bitcoin-reserve-bill/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">there&#8217;s a similar bill in Pennsylvania&#8217;s House of Representatives</a>. </p>



<p>This trend is also growing internationally. Last month, a presidential candidate in Poland&#8217;s upcoming election <a href="https://beincrypto.com/poland-slawomir-mentzen-promises-bitcoin-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">vowed to implement a Bitcoin Reserve if elected</a>. A Representative in the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/russia-strategic-bitcoin-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Russian State Duma filed a similar bill this week</a>. In other words, there could be a counterweight to arguments against a US Bitcoin Reserve.</p>



<p>After all, if several countries are creating national reserves, it would be disadvantageous to deliberately kneecap the US. In any event, Capriglione&#8217;s effort to create a reserve in Texas could serve as a bellwether. The state is heavily controlled by Trump&#8217;s party, but will its rank-and-file representatives support Bitcoin? Only time will tell.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/texas-bitcoin-reserve-capriglione/">Texas State Representative Introduces Bill to Create Bitcoin Reserve</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BIC_bitcoin_highs__alltimehigh_growing-covers_positive.png" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BIC_bitcoin_highs__alltimehigh_growing-covers_positive.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CoinShares Forecasts a Strong 2025 for Bitcoin, and Altcoins Under Donald Trump</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/coinshares-forecasts-strong-2025-for-crypto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 07:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Markets News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=626789</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>CoinShares projects altcoins to outperform Bitcoin in 2025 under Trump's regulatory changes, alongside the rise of Bitcoin-yielding companies.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/coinshares-forecasts-strong-2025-for-crypto/">CoinShares Forecasts a Strong 2025 for Bitcoin, and Altcoins Under Donald Trump</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>As 2024 draws to a close, European crypto investment firm CoinShares has released market predictions for the new year. In its report, CoinShares has identified the key trends that could dominate the crypto industry in 2025.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The report closely examines how the US under President Donald Trump could impact the crypto market. It also discusses the emergence of Bitcoin-yielding companies as a trend to be monitored in 2025.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-trump-to-overhaul-crypto"><strong>Trump to Overhaul Crypto?</strong></h2>



<p>In a <a href="https://coinshares.com/en/d/resources/research/2025-outlook/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">report</a> dated December 11, CoinShares said that the US is expected to undergo significant changes in crypto regulation in 2025 under the Trump administration. Analyst Max Shannon believes the promised regulatory overhaul and support for Bitcoin miners could create a favorable environment for digital assets in 2025.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“As the US shifts towards these policies, altcoins are likely to outperform <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/getting-paid-in-crypto/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin</a>, despite the latter still potentially being one of the best performing assets in 2025,” the analyst wrote.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It was predicted that miners focused solely on mining Bitcoin would likely outperform those who have diversified into other revenue streams, such as AI or machine manufacturing.</p>



<p>CoinShares further noted that the road ahead for <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/how-to-prepare-bitcoin-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin ETFs</a> looks promising, given their rapid success. Also, only 20% of the AUM in <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-etfs-surge-as-liquidations-hit-billions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin ETFs</a> is held by professional firms and money managers. This means there is room for growth with more institutional adoption.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-bitcoin-yielding-the-next-big-thing">Bitcoin Yielding &#8211; The Next Big Thing?</h2>



<p>Another trend to be mindful of in 2025 is the emergence of <span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"><a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitwise-predicts-bitcoin-200k-crypto-market-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bit</a><a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitwise-predicts-bitcoin-200k-crypto-market-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">coin-yielding</a> companies. This comes into focus as businesses are now adopting</span> BTC as a treasury asset.</p>



<p>Analyst Satish Patel has classified BTC yield into three categories. The first is the growth of Bitcoin holdings relative to the company’s shares. The second is yield farming, which generates returns by lending Bitcoin.</p>



<p>The third category involves alternative strategies for leveraging derivatives to generate income from a Bitcoin reserve.</p>



<p>MicroStrategy, holding 423,650 BTC, has even introduced its own version of the “BTC Yield” metric to measure the effectiveness of its strategy. Companies like Block, Marathon Digital, and Metaplanet are following in MicroStrategy’s footsteps as they accumulate Bitcoin to use for profits.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“This trend reflects a broader recognition of Bitcoin’s potential to serve not only as a store of value but also as a means to generate yields,” the analyst said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Patel also highlighted how several major companies have started accepting crypto as payment in 2024. He believes companies like Amazon, Shopify, and Nike, which are already involved in crypto, either through payments or investments, may consider incorporating Bitcoin into their treasuries in 2025.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-2025-holds-for-ethereum-solana">What 2025 Holds for Ethereum, Solana</h2>



<p>When it comes to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-bull-run-to-resume/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum</a>, CoinShares predicted that usage on Layer 2s will continue to increase over the next year. According to analyst Luke Nolan, the institutionalization of Layer 2 chains, as was the case with Kraken and Sony, will drive adoption in 2025.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“In our view, L2 adoption will continue to rise, which will increase demand for blobs, and Ethereum transaction fee spend,” the analyst said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He further added that L2s would once again become a source of demand for Ethereum.</p>



<p>As <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-pectra-update-game-changer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum prepares for the Pectra upgrade</a> in 2025, the analyst noted that executing the roadmap would bring new efficiencies. The ETH token will also face challenges as it attempts to balance usability and value accrual.</p>



<p>Now, as far as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-sol-price-down-from-all-time-high-more-declines/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Solana’s</a> future is concerned, the report said that Frankendancer and Firedancer can transform it.</p>



<p>These are validator clients that aim to change up Solana’s networking, runtime, and consensus layers for improved performance and scalability. Nevertheless, Solana also needs to address its transactions per second (TPS) limitations through updates for greater efficiency.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/coinshares-forecasts-strong-2025-for-crypto/">CoinShares Forecasts a Strong 2025 for Bitcoin, and Altcoins Under Donald Trump</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_Bitcoin_Bullish_positive_market_up-3.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_Bitcoin_Bullish_positive_market_up-3.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vancouver Council Embraces Bitcoin Reserve Proposal Amidst Fiat Concerns</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/vancouver-council-embraces-bitcoin-reserve-proposal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 07:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=626753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Vancouver’s city council has approved exploring Bitcoin as part of its financial reserves. A feasibility report in 2025 will determine its adoption.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/vancouver-council-embraces-bitcoin-reserve-proposal/">Vancouver Council Embraces Bitcoin Reserve Proposal Amidst Fiat Concerns</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Following a recent mayoral proposal, Vancouver&#8217;s city council has approved a motion to explore integrating Bitcoin (BTC) into the city&#8217;s financial strategy.</strong></p>



<p>The decision demonstrates a forward-thinking strategy, focusing on diversifying the Canadian city’s financial portfolio while tackling issues related to fiat currency volatility and inflation.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-vancouver-to-become-a-bitcoin-friendly-city"><strong>Vancouver</strong> To Become a Bitcoin-Friendly City</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://csg001-harmony.sliq.net/00317/Harmony/en/PowerBrowser/PowerBrowserV2/20241127/-1/20611" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">motion</a>, spearheaded by <a href="https://beincrypto.com/vancouver-mayor-bitcoin-reserve-proposal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mayor Ken Sim</a>, includes creating a Bitcoin reserve and enabling BTC as a payment option for taxes and city fees. Mayor Sim framed the initiative as a measure to enhance financial stability.</p>



<p>Specifically, Sim said it would be irresponsible for the City of Vancouver not to consider the merits of adding Bitcoin to the City’s strategic assets. As it happened, the city council approved the proposal.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Vancouver city council approves motion 3. Preserving of the City’s Purchasing Power through Diversification of Financial Reserves – Becoming a Bitcoin-Friendly City,” Vancouver city clerk <a href="https://x.com/VanCityClerk/status/1866988118496383021" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">shared</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This initiative marks a dramatic shift from previous city policies. In 2019, former Mayor Kennedy Stewart attempted to ban <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-are-bitcoin-atms-and-how-do-they-work/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin ATMs</a> within Vancouver, despite the city being <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-atm-locations-canada-jump-28-last-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">home to the world’s first Bitcoin ATM</a>. The latest development, therefore, reflects Vancouver’s growth into a potentially Bitcoin-friendly city.</p>



<p>The council directed city staff to evaluate the feasibility and implications of adopting Bitcoin. A report of this feasibility study is due by the first quarter (Q1) of 2025. The proposal highlights Bitcoin’s potential to act as a hedge against the debasement of fiat currencies. Specifically, it would safeguard the city’s purchasing power.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Diversifying the City of Vancouver&#8217;s financial reserves and payment options to include Bitcoin would not only enhance the resilience of our city’s financial portfolio but ultimately benefit taxpayers,” the motion elaborates.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The move comes amidst growing global optimism in the cryptocurrency sector, particularly following pro-crypto candidate <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-price-sets-new-ath/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donald Trump’s reelection in the US</a>. Market watchers expect this political shift to bolster regulatory clarity and adoption. Vancouver’s Bitcoin-friendly stance may position the city as a trailblazer in municipal crypto adoption.</p>



<p>Mayor Sim, a vocal advocate for Bitcoin, described it as “the greatest invention in human history” during an interview. This further highlights his enthusiasm for integrating digital assets into public finance. The proposal has also caught the attention of cryptocurrency proponents worldwide.</p>



<p>With this approval, Vancouver is joining other progressive cities that are experimenting with Bitcoin. Once implemented, it would set a precedent for municipalities to modernize their financial strategies.</p>



<p>For now, however, the success of this initiative will depend on the findings of the upcoming feasibility report. It will assess potential risks, implementation challenges, and long-term benefits as part of the discovery phase.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Excited to see what comes from the discovery phase,” one user <a href="https://x.com/SpeedAmbassador/status/1867074175258800198" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">commented</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/vancouver-council-embraces-bitcoin-reserve-proposal/">Vancouver Council Embraces Bitcoin Reserve Proposal Amidst Fiat Concerns</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bic_Bitcoin_BEP2_BTCB_3-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bic_Bitcoin_BEP2_BTCB_3-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MicroStrategy to Enter Nasdaq 100 This Month, Claim ETF Analysts</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/microstrategy-nasdaq-100-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Landon Manning]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 23:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=626631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>MicroStrategy may join the Nasdaq 100 this month, driven by its Bitcoin investments. Analysts see a clear path unless reclassified as a finance firm.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/microstrategy-nasdaq-100-list/">MicroStrategy to Enter Nasdaq 100 This Month, Claim ETF Analysts</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>According to Eric Balchunas and James Seyffart, two respected ETF analysts, MicroStrategy may soon enter the Nasdaq 100. MicroStrategy is still classified as a tech stock, circumventing the restriction that finance companies are ineligible.   </strong></p>



<p>If this prediction comes true, it will take place this Friday for a listing on December 23. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-microstrategy-on-nasdaq-100">MicroStrategy on Nasdaq 100?</h2>



<p>Balchunas first declared this prediction via social media post yesterday, claiming that MicroStrategy would replace Moderna, a COVID-19 vaccine manufacturer. </p>



<p>Driven by its consecutive Bitcoin purchases, MicroStrategy&#8217;s stock price has been surging, and it has recently become one of the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/microstrategy-market-cap-hits-milestone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">top 100 publicly traded US companies</a>. However, NASDAQ must approve it to put it on the list.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="954" height="388" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-71.png" alt="Expected Additions to Nasdaq 100" class="wp-image-626641" style="aspect-ratio:2.4587628865979383;width:838px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-71.png 954w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-71-360x146.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-71-850x346.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-71-768x312.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-71-150x61.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 954px) 100vw, 954px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Expected Additions to Nasdaq 100. Source: <a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1866595936983716168#m" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eric Balchunas</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>As a publicly traded company, Nasdaq has made limited entries to the crypto industry in recent years. Last year, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/nasdaq-halts-crypto-custody-plans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SEC halted its plans to launch a crypto custody business</a>, and the exchange hasn&#8217;t publicly discussed restarting them. </p>



<p>In August, it did facilitate BlackRock&#8217;s efforts to get <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-nasdaq-options-trading-spot-ethereum-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">options trading on its Ethereum ETF</a>. Beyond that, however, Nasdaq has been quiet on the crypto front. </p>



<p>Meanwhile, James Seyffart <a href="https://x.com/JSeyff/status/1866870864798486529#m" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">concurred</a> with Balchunas&#8217; opinions via another post. He pointed out that Nasdaq does not permit finance companies to be on its list, and MicroStrategy may technically qualify. </p>



<p>The company&#8217;s fate is <a href="https://beincrypto.com/microstrategy-stock-hits-all-time-high/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">inexorably tied to Bitcoin&#8217;s performance</a>, and thus, it is arguably a finance company. However, it&#8217;s currently listed as a tech stock, and it can&#8217;t be reassessed until March.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Here are the dates for ICB [Industry Classification Benchmark] reclassification. So unless they&#8217;ve already started the process of reclassifying MicroStrategy as a financials stock&#8230; we think it should be in. That said &#8212; this is the primary risk for not getting included in my opinion,&#8221; Seyffart <a href="https://x.com/JSeyff/status/1866872350882541931#m" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">claimed</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Indeed, MicroStrategy is <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/who-owns-the-most-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one of the world&#8217;s largest Bitcoin whales</a>, but the firm started as a tech company. Even though it <a href="https://beincrypto.com/microstrategy-bitcoin-purchase-2-1-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">routinely invests huge amounts of capital into Bitcoin</a>, which contributed primarily to its 500% stock market growth this year, MicroStrategy is still a tech stock in Nasdaq&#8217;s consideration. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="2592" height="946" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-3.16.23-PM.png" alt="MicroStrategy (MSTR) YTD Stock Performance" class="wp-image-626642" style="aspect-ratio:2.7399577167019027;width:1013px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-3.16.23-PM.png 2592w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-3.16.23-PM-360x131.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-3.16.23-PM-850x310.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-3.16.23-PM-768x280.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-3.16.23-PM-1536x561.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-3.16.23-PM-2048x747.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-3.16.23-PM-150x55.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2592px) 100vw, 2592px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">MicroStrategy (MSTR) YTD Stock Performance. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/NASDAQ-MSTR/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Ultimately, this is only a prediction, albeit one from two seasoned ETF analysts. In any event, there are important deadlines to consider. If MicroStrategy is entering the Nasdaq 100, the announcement will come by the end of the week. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/microstrategy-nasdaq-100-list/">MicroStrategy to Enter Nasdaq 100 This Month, Claim ETF Analysts</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/bic_Michael_Saylor_bitcoin_positive_2.png" medium="image" width="5120" height="2880" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/bic_Michael_Saylor_bitcoin_positive_2.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin ETFs Attract $439 Million Daily Inflows Despite Market Downturn</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-etfs-surge-as-liquidations-hit-billions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mohammad Shahid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 20:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Markets News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=626596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin ETFs are in a bullish run, extending positive inflows for nine consecutive days, even as the broader crypto market faces significant liquidations.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-etfs-surge-as-liquidations-hit-billions/">Bitcoin ETFs Attract $439 Million Daily Inflows Despite Market Downturn</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Bitcoin ETFs are showing no signs of weakness as they enter the ninth consecutive day of positive inflows, even as the broader market experiences a downtrend.</strong></p>



<p>BlackRock’s spot <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrocks-ibit-etf-europe-surpass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin ETF</a> IBIT led with the most inflows over the past day.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-bitcoin-etfs-nbsp-extend-the-bullish-momentum">Bitcoin ETFs&nbsp;Extend the Bullish Momentum</h2>



<p>According to the data from SoSoValue, Bitcoin ETFs extended their winning streak after recording the ninth consecutive day of positive inflows on December 10. Last week, all 12 funds recorded the second-largest weekly inflow at $2.73 billion. Despite wider liquidation in the market this week, ETF investors seem highly bullish on the funds. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1788" height="608" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214445.png" alt="US Spot Bitcoin ETFs daily inflow chart" class="wp-image-626597" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214445.png 1788w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214445-360x122.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214445-850x289.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214445-768x261.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214445-1536x522.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214445-150x51.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1788px) 100vw, 1788px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Total Bitcoin spot ETF net inflow. Source: <a href="https://sosovalue.com/assets/etf/Total_Crypto_Spot_ETF_Fund_Flow?page=usBTC" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SoSoValue</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>The ETFs attracted a significant amount of $439.56 million on Tuesday as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrocks-ibit-etf-europe-surpass/">BlackRock’s IBIT</a> brought in $295.63 million, followed by Fidelity’s FBTC, with an inflow of $210.48 million.</p>



<p>At the same time, Grayscale’s GBTC recorded outflows of over $60 million. Nevertheless, the $400 million in net inflows confirm the strong investor interest in the US spot <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-bitcoin-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BTC ETFs</a>.</p>



<p>The total net assets under these ETFs have crossed $107.76 billion, which marks 5.65% of Bitcoin’s total market cap. More interestingly, these funds currently hold <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-bitcoin-etfs-surpass-satoshi-btc-holdings/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more Bitcoin than Satoshi Nakamoto</a>.</p>



<p>In November, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-etfs-record-inflow-drive-btc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin ETFs recorded $6.1 billion</a> in inflows, the highest monthly influx since their launch in January. Total inflows in December are already nearing $4 billion, and if the momentum holds, the funds could hit a new record this month.</p>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/where-to-buy-ethereum-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum ETFs</a> did not disappoint either, as daily inflows crossed $305 million on Tuesday. But the same can not be said about the rest of the market.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-crypto-liquidations-soar-to-billions-nbsp"><strong>Crypto Liquidations Soar to Billions</strong>&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Despite the growth shown by the ETF market, the past couple of days saw mounting liquidations as Bitcoin could not hold firm above $100,000. Bitcoin dragged the rest of the market down with it as the total crypto market cap took a hit. Major altcoins like XRP and Solana also mirrored Bitcoin’s losses. </p>



<p>According to Coinglass data, the market recorded $1.7 billion in liquidations on December 9 alone as Bitcoin prices declined to around $97,000 after hitting $100,000.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1770" height="500" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214351-1.png" alt="crypto liquidation" class="wp-image-626601" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214351-1.png 1770w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214351-1-360x102.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214351-1-850x240.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214351-1-768x217.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214351-1-1536x434.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-214351-1-150x42.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1770px) 100vw, 1770px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Total liquidations chart. Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/LiquidationData" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Coinglass</a><br></figcaption></figure>



<p>The sell-off continued into the week, with the total liquidations over the past three days topping $2.5 billion. </p>



<p>However, Bitcoin recovered at press time and was trading around $100,555, up 5.06% over the past 24 hours. If Bitcoin manages to stay above the $100,000 mark, then the largest cryptocurrency can continue to cement its position in institutional portfolios. </p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-etfs-surge-as-liquidations-hit-billions/">Bitcoin ETFs Attract $439 Million Daily Inflows Despite Market Downturn</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/bic_Bitcoin_etf_ETFs_General_1-covers_neutral.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/bic_Bitcoin_etf_ETFs_General_1-covers_neutral.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goldman Sachs Awaits Regulatory Changes to Deepen Involvement in Bitcoin, and Ethereum</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/goldman-sachs-regulatory-shift-bitcoin-ethereum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 08:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=624725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Goldman Sachs is poised to enter the crypto market, but only if the U.S. regulatory framework evolves, says CEO David Solomon, aligning with Trump's pro-crypto stance.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/goldman-sachs-regulatory-shift-bitcoin-ethereum/">Goldman Sachs Awaits Regulatory Changes to Deepen Involvement in Bitcoin, and Ethereum</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Goldman Sachs CEO has confirmed that the investment bank is open to engaging with cryptocurrencies if the regulatory environment changes under President Donald Trump.</strong></p>



<p>According to the CEO, US regulations need to be more conducive for the asset manager to enter the crypto market.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-goldman-sachs-ceo-asks-for-a-change-in-regulations">Goldman Sachs CEO Asks for a Change in Regulations</h2>



<p>Speaking at a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VTf5_yiQ39Y" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Reuters conference</a>, CEO David Solomon said on Tuesday that the existing regulatory framework has to evolve so that the company can invest directly in Bitcoin and Ethereum. He added that there is a lot of attention around the crypto space now, but it is still unclear how the regulations will change under the new administration.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;For the moment, our ability to act in these (crypto) markets is extremely limited from a regulatory perspective,&#8221; the CEO said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He further clarified that though Goldman Sachs has explored digital assets, as a regulated financial institution, it can not buy or sell cryptocurrencies like <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitwise-predicts-bitcoin-200k-crypto-market-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin</a> or <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-price-high-as-whales-increase-accumulation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum</a> at the moment.</p>



<p>However, the company does own significant holdings in <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-bitcoin-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin ETFs</a>. According to a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/886982/000076999324000444/xslForm13F_X02/Infotable_Q3-2024.xml" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">filing</a> with the Securities and Exchange Commission from November 14, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/goldman-sachs-drw-capital-bitcoin-ethereum-etf-holdings/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Goldman Sachs holds about $718 million in eight ETFs</a>. The bank has made an investment of $461 million in BlackRock’s <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrocks-ibit-etf-europe-surpass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin ETF</a>, among others.</p>



<p>Goldman Sachs CEO David Solomon&#8217;s comments come as President-elect <a href="https://beincrypto.com/donald-trump-appoints-crypto-czar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donald Trump</a> has promised a crypto-friendly government. </p>



<p>With his choice of crypto advocate Paul Atkins as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-pro-crypto-paul-atkins-sec-chair/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SEC chief</a>, the president seems to be staying true to his promises. The SEC is now more likely to adopt a friendlier approach towards crypto investors. </p>



<p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/12/10/trump-administration-tech-moguls-ai-crypto" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Axios</a>&#8216; sources have revealed that Donald Trump apparently &#8220;would love&#8221; for Bitcoin to keep rising and eventually pass $150,000 after he takes office.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s another stock market for him. Trump would love for Bitcoin to hit $150,000 early in his presidency,&#8221; a top transition source said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This was after Trump took credit for Bitcoin’s meteoric rise to an all-time high of $100,000 last week.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Congratulations Bitcoiners! $100,000! You&#8217;re Welcome!!!&#8221; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/113600319916325790" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">posted</a>. </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/goldman-sachs-regulatory-shift-bitcoin-ethereum/">Goldman Sachs Awaits Regulatory Changes to Deepen Involvement in Bitcoin, and Ethereum</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bic_donald_trump_usa_neutral_4.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bic_donald_trump_usa_neutral_4.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitwise Predicts Bitcoin at $200,000 and Major Gains for Crypto Stocks in 2025</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/bitwise-predicts-bitcoin-200k-crypto-market-2025/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mohammad Shahid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=624688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitwise forecasts Bitcoin at $200,000, record highs for Ethereum and Solana, and major growth in crypto stocks by 2025.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitwise-predicts-bitcoin-200k-crypto-market-2025/">Bitwise Predicts Bitcoin at $200,000 and Major Gains for Crypto Stocks in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Asset management firm Bitwise has issued ten highly optimistic predictions for the crypto market in 2025. </strong><strong><br></strong><br>Among these, Bitcoin is expected to reach $200,000 by the end of next year, and companies holding significant crypto investments could see substantial stock market growth.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-bitwise-predicts-2025-to-be-the-golden-year-for-crypto">Bitwise Predicts 2025 to Be the Golden Year for Crypto</h2>



<p>The firm <a href="https://bitwiseinvestments.com/crypto-market-insights/the-year-ahead-10-crypto-predictions-for-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">anticipates</a> record highs for Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Solana. While Bitcoin and Solana recently hit new peaks, Ethereum has lagged. </p>



<p>However, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-tvl-increases-surpasses-solana-tron/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum’s total value locked (TVL)</a> has climbed to its highest since 2022, signaling the potential for a rebound. For Solana, it’s an easier consideration, as meme coin activity on the network has consecutively created several bullish cycles for SOL this year.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“The media wants to portray crypto&#8217;s political efforts in a negative light. It&#8217;s actually how democracy works. If you face what you think is inappropriate regulation, you&#8217;re only possible responses are the one listed above,” <a href="https://x.com/Matt_Hougan/status/1865152088155787346" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a> Matt Hougan, CIO of Bitwise.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Bitwise also projects that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/gemini-vs-coinbase/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coinbase</a> will join the S&amp;P 500, and MicroStrategy will enter the Nasdaq-100. These developments would significantly increase crypto exposure for US investors.  These predictions have already started to materialize.</p>



<p>Bloomberg ETF analysts expect MicroStrategy to be added to the Nasdaq-100 by December 23, with announcements expected this week.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“MSTR is likely to be added to $QQQ on 12/23 (w/ announcement coming 12/13). Moderna likely to get boot (symbolic). S&amp;P 500 add next year probably. Again this is our best estimate of what will go down. We don&#8217;t work at Nasdaq,” ETF Analyst Eric Balchunas <a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1866595936983716168" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a> on X (formerly Twitter). </p>
</blockquote>



<p>This is based on the fact that MicroStrategy’s stock price has increased by nearly 450% YTD. Also, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-reaches-100k/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin’s $100,000 milestone</a> has propelled the company into the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/microstrategy-market-cap-hits-milestone/">top 100 public US firms</a>.</p>



<p>Also, Bitwise foresees a doubling in the number of countries holding Bitcoin in their reserves. These projects are not far-fetched. As BeInCrypto reported earlier, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/russia-strategic-bitcoin-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Russian lawmakers are already proposing</a> a national Bitcoin reserve. Canada’s <a href="https://beincrypto.com/vancouver-mayor-bitcoin-reserve-proposal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vancouver is exploring a similar initiative</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1106" height="448" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-64.png" alt="countries that hold Bitcoin" class="wp-image-624689" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-64.png 1106w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-64-360x146.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-64-850x344.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-64-768x311.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-64-150x61.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1106px) 100vw, 1106px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Countries that Hold Bitcoin. Source: <a href="https://treasuries.bitbo.io/countries/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Bitcoin Treasuries</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Meanwhile, in the US, there’s strong optimism for a Bitcoin reserve, as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/donald-trump-pro-crypto-election-victory/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trump promised during his election campaign</a>. The report also predicts a sharp increase in stablecoin market assets, potentially reaching $400 billion, supported by anticipated US legislation. </p>



<p>Earlier today, Ripple had the green light from NY regulators to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ripple-stablecoin-rlusd-new-york-approval/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launch its RLUSD stablecoin</a>, which could indicate massive growth for the US <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/best-stablecoins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stablecoin market</a>. </p>



<p>Overall, it’s evident that Bitwise’s predictions are seemingly aligned with the current industry activities. So, it won’t be a major surprise if all of these estimates become a reality in 2025.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitwise-predicts-bitcoin-200k-crypto-market-2025/">Bitwise Predicts Bitcoin at $200,000 and Major Gains for Crypto Stocks in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/BIC_Bitwise_3-covers.png" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/BIC_Bitwise_3-covers.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Votes Against Bitcoin Investment Proposal </title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/shareholders-reject-microsoft-bitcoin-proposal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mohammad Shahid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=624155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft shareholders rejected a proposal to invest in Bitcoin, citing risks, as Amazon explores a bold $88 billion Bitcoin strategy.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/shareholders-reject-microsoft-bitcoin-proposal/">Microsoft Votes Against Bitcoin Investment Proposal </a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Microsoft shareholders voted against Michael Saylor’s proposal to invest in Bitcoin to diversify its portfolio. <br></strong><br>The shareholder vote took place on Tuesday, December 10, and the majority of the MSFT shareholders voted against the proposal. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-microsoft-won-t-be-investing-in-bitcoin">Microsoft Won’t be Investing in Bitcoin</h2>



<p>Michael Saylor <a href="https://x.com/saylor/status/1863323760511627565" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">prepared</a> a 3-minute presentation on December 1, urging the Microsoft board to add Bitcoin to its portfolio. The MicroStrategy CEO said Bitcoin is the seventh largest asset in the world, and its market cap will soon reach $2 trillion.<br><br>Less than a week after Saylor’s proposal, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-reaches-100k/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin soared to its $100,000 milestone</a> and, as Saylor had predicted, achieved over a $2 trillion market cap. He also projected that Bitcoin would reach over <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitwise-predicts-bitcoin-200k-crypto-market-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$200 trillion in market cap</a> by 2045.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, these proposals weren’t enough to persuade Microsoft’s shareholders. As BeInCrypto reported earlier, the company’s board <a href="https://beincrypto.com/microsoft-shareholders-bitcoin-investment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cautioned shareholders against this proposal</a>, saying that it would add &#8220;unnecessary&#8221; risks.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p><a href="https://x.com/Microsoft"><br></a>&#8220;Microsoft shareholders reject the proposal for a strategic Bitcoin reserve. In 5 years, they’ll understand. Everyone buys Bitcoin at the price they deserve. BTC doesn’t wait. It simply transfers wealth to those who see,&#8221; Saylor <a href="https://x.com/Saylorsatsire/status/1866537616285241737" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">posted</a> on X (formerly Twitter)</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, Microsoft’s stock market competitor, Amazon, is taking a different approach. Yesterday, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/amazon-shareholders-propose-bitcoin-treasury/">Amazon’s stakeholders proposed</a> allocating $88 billion of its cash reserves to invest in Bitcoin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This contrasting approach highlights the differing strategies major corporations are adopting regarding cryptocurrency as an investment asset.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Bitcoin doesn&#8217;t care about Microsoft, but eventually Microsoft will care about Bitcoin,&#8221; popular entrepreneur and investor Anthony Pompliano&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/APompliano/status/1866543644561310181" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a> on X. </p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/bitcoin-price-prediction/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin&#8217;s price</a> briefly reacted to this news, dipping to $94,000 earlier today. However, since then, the asset has recovered and currently sits at around $96,400. However, Microsoft&#8217;s stock price (MSFT) is seemingly unaffected by the news. The company&#8217;s stock is up by nearly 20% year-to-date, which is a far cry from <a href="https://beincrypto.com/microstrategy-market-cap-hits-milestone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MicroStrategy&#8217;s staggering 450% growth</a> this year. </p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/shareholders-reject-microsoft-bitcoin-proposal/">Microsoft Votes Against Bitcoin Investment Proposal </a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/bic_Microsoft-covers_neutral-2.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/bic_Microsoft-covers_neutral-2.jpg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
