<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Altcoin News Today - BeInCrypto</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-news/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:01:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/cropped-bic_favic-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Altcoin News Today - BeInCrypto</title>
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-news/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Crypto Analyst Miles Deutscher Identifies Altcoins Primed for Retail Surge</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/miles-deutscher-identifies-promising-altcoins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=627247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Crypto analyst Miles Deutscher reveals a list of retail-friendly altcoins, emphasizing accessibility and new exchange listings as growth drivers.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/miles-deutscher-identifies-promising-altcoins/">Crypto Analyst Miles Deutscher Identifies Altcoins Primed for Retail Surge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Prominent cryptocurrency analyst Miles Deutscher has pinpointed a list of altcoins he believes are poised to outperform as retail interest surges back into the market.</strong></p>



<p>According to Deutscher, retail investors are taking the &#8220;path of least resistance,&#8221; favoring easily accessible coins listed on major centralized exchanges (CEXs) like Binance, Coinbase, Upbit, and Robinhood.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-retail-interest-fuels-the-crypto-market"><strong>Retail Interest Fuels the Crypto Market</strong></h2>



<p>Deutscher points to a spike in Google search volumes for cryptocurrencies as evidence of rising retail interest. As new investors flood the market, they tend to gravitate toward well-known platforms and straightforward investment options.</p>



<p>Coins like Ripple (<a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/ripple/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">XRP</a>), Cardano (ADA), and Algorand (<a href="https://beincrypto.com/algo-token-price-eyes-new-highs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ALGO</a>) are now gaining attention due to their widespread availability on major exchanges. Of note is that these altcoins have been underperforming in recent months. </p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“It&#8217;s obvious which altcoins are going to outperform this cycle…There are 16,057 cryptos listed on CoinGecko, but I’ve narrowed it down to just 90. These are the alts with the BEST chance of catching a huge retail bid,” Deutscher <a href="https://x.com/milesdeutscher/status/1866924824901325009" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://x.com/milesdeutscher/status/1866924847353446568"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" width="1076" height="579" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-2.png" alt="Spike in Google search volumes for altcoins" class="wp-image-627295" style="aspect-ratio:1.8583765112262522;width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-2.png 1076w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-2-360x194.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-2-850x457.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-2-768x413.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LINKUSDT_2024-12-12_11-54-03-2-150x81.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1076px) 100vw, 1076px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Spike in Google Search Volume for Altcoins</figcaption></figure>



<p>To identify the altcoins with the best chances of success, Deutscher leveraged data from the APIs of top exchanges. He then created a custom spreadsheet of 90 tokens. Among the standout picks are Aptos (APT), <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dormant-dogecoins-awaken/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dogecoin</a> (DOGE), Chainlink (LINK), and Near Protocol (NEAR). Others include Solana (SOL), XRP, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ondo-finance-tvl-surges-amid-rwa-tokenization-hearing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ondo Finance</a> (ONDO), Pepe (PEPE), Sei (SEI), and Stacks (STX).</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“These coins have maximum global accessibility because they are listed across all major exchanges. If retail wants to bid on altcoins, those with the easiest access will perform the best. Coins like APT, DOGE, and SOL check all the boxes for accessibility, volume, and retail interest,” Deutscher emphasized.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-why-accessibility-matters-risk-and-opportunity"><strong>Why Accessibility Matters: Risk and Opportunity</strong></h2>



<p>Deutscher <a href="https://x.com/milesdeutscher/status/1866924941221958112" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">argues</a> that accessibility is critical in driving retail investments. Exchanges like <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/binance-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Binance</a> and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/coinbase-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coinbase</a> dominate user volume globally. Meanwhile, platforms like <a href="https://beincrypto.com/south-koreas-regulator-flags-upbit-kyc-violations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Upbit</a> and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/buy-crypto-robinhood/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Robinhood</a> cater to specific regional markets and novice investors.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Retail investors follow the path of least resistance. If a coin is listed on all major exchanges, it ensures maximum exposure and simplifies the buying process for new entrants,&#8221; he reiterated.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In addition to accessibility, Deutscher highlighted the relatively favorable risk-to-reward (R/R) ratio of many CEX-listed altcoins. While they may not have the extreme volatility of smaller, on-chain tokens, many offer significant upside potential in the range of 5–10x gains. He also advised investors to keep an eye on upcoming listings, which can present unique opportunities.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“New listings on major exchanges are a catalyst for price action. Coins like MOG and MEW, which recently secured some high-profile listings, show how accessibility drives interest,” he <a href="https://x.com/milesdeutscher/status/1866925057513345442" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Deutscher advises investors looking to gain an edge to dive deeper into projects by participating in community discussions and monitoring announcements for hints of potential listings.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Listen to project AMAs and join their Telegram and Discord groups. The more information you can extract about future exchange listings, the better your chances of positioning yourself early,” Deutscher <a href="https://x.com/milesdeutscher/status/1866925081110384727" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">suggested</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>As retail interest in cryptocurrency ramps up, Deutscher’s insights offer a roadmap for trading this phase of the market cycle. Focusing on accessibility, fundamentals, and community-driven catalysts, the selected altcoins could be well-positioned for significant gains. Nevertheless, traders and investors must also conduct their own research.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/miles-deutscher-identifies-promising-altcoins/">Crypto Analyst Miles Deutscher Identifies Altcoins Primed for Retail Surge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_altcoins_neutral.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_altcoins_neutral.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CryptoQuant CEO Analyzes Reasons Behind Altcoin Season’s Delay</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/delay-of-altcoin-season-cryptoquant/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=615870</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Altseason remains delayed as Bitcoin’s ETF-driven rally absorbs institutional focus. While Solana thrives, smaller altcoins struggle, emphasizing the need for innovation and fresh capital.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/delay-of-altcoin-season-cryptoquant/">CryptoQuant CEO Analyzes Reasons Behind Altcoin Season’s Delay</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The cryptocurrency market is buzzing with discussions about the delayed onset of the altcoin season. While Bitcoin has surged due to institutional interest and spot ETF (exchange-traded funds) demand, the altcoin market remains relatively subdued.</strong></p>



<p>Analysts and industry insiders are dissecting the factors behind this phenomenon, revealing a technical interplay of capital flows, investor behavior, and market events.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-diverging-opinions-on-delayed-altcoin-season"><strong>Diverging Opinions on Delayed Altcoin Season</strong></h2>



<p>Ki Young Ju, CEO of CryptoQuant, argues that the current Bitcoin (<a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BTC</a>) rally differs significantly from previous cycles. In a detailed thread on X (formerly Twitter), he explained that the nature of capital flowing into Bitcoin has shifted. <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-etfs-could-overtake-satoshi-stash/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Institutional investors and spot ETFs</a> are now driving Bitcoin&#8217;s growth rather than retail traders on crypto exchanges.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“These institutional investors and ETF buyers have no intention of rotating their assets from Bitcoin to altcoins,” Ki Young Ju <a href="https://x.com/ki_young_ju/status/1861693773086081273" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He emphasized that these players operate outside of crypto exchanges, making asset rotation less feasible. Moreover, smaller altcoins depend heavily on exchange users for liquidity, which has been lacking in this cycle.</p>



<p>CryptoQuant CEO suggested that fresh capital must flow into crypto exchanges for altcoins to achieve new all-time highs — a trend not yet evident. While institutional funds might venture into major altcoins, minor ones remain reliant on retail traders.</p>



<p>Ki Young Ju concluded that altcoins need independent strategies to attract fresh capital rather than riding Bitcoin’s momentum. Despite this cautious outlook, he remains optimistic.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Altseason will come, but it’ll be selective. Not every altcoin will hit its previous ATH,” he added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Not everyone agrees with CryptoQuant CEO&#8217;s analysis. CryptoVizArt, a senior analyst and researcher at Glassnode, believes altseason has already begun. He highlighted Solana’s explosive growth in active addresses, which now number 18.6 million per day—nearly 40X that of Ethereum.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Retail has already chosen where to gamble in this cycle,” CryptoVizArt <a href="https://x.com/CryptoVizArt/status/1861694334338273508" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">noted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The researcher pointed to the popularity of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/meme-coins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">meme coins</a> and Solana-based projects as evidence of altseason in progress. However, Ki Young Ju partially aligned with this view.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Altseason has started for a few major altcoins, but not for others,” the CryptoQuant executive <a href="https://x.com/ki_young_ju/status/1861695722749563090" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">noted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Other analysts, like Crypto Feras, take a more historical perspective. In their view, altseason traditionally occurs in the latter stages of Bitcoin’s cycle.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“In 2020, altcoins were crushed during Bitcoin’s glorious run in H2, only to rally later,” Feras <a href="https://x.com/CryptoFeras/status/1861771553949601906" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>They argue that the sheer number of altcoins today dilutes capital inflows, making the current cycle’s altseason less impactful than previous ones.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-psychology-of-market-cycles"><strong>The Psychology of Market Cycles</strong></h2>



<p>XForceGlobal, another prominent community member, offered a nuanced critique of Ki Young Ju’s argument, highlighting the role of psychology and the dominance metric in understanding market behavior.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“It’s impossible to measure the allocation of institutions versus exchange users. The market operates as a self-fulfilling prophecy,” they <a href="https://x.com/XForceGlobal/status/1861754533384487327" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>They pointed out that altseason often lags Bitcoin’s rally, with confidence in Bitcoin typically translating into altcoin growth.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Altcoins will always lag, but once money flow aligns, an altseason is inevitable,” XForceGlobal concluded.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Adding to the discussion, indicators such as the Ethereum-to-Bitcoin (<a href="https://beincrypto.com/eth-btc-ratio-sinks-to-lowest/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ETH/BTC</a>) ratio hitting historic lows suggest a possible shift in the market. Similarly, BeInCrypto also reported on <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-approaches/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">altcoins being poised for growth</a>, supported by rising sentiment and key technical indicators.</p>



<p>However, the total altcoin market cap remains below its all-time high, echoing Ki Young Ju’s concern about the lack of fresh liquidity from exchange users.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1545" height="747" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/TOTAL2_2024-11-28_12-41-20.png" alt="Total Altcoin Market Cap" class="wp-image-615881" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/TOTAL2_2024-11-28_12-41-20.png 1545w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/TOTAL2_2024-11-28_12-41-20-360x174.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/TOTAL2_2024-11-28_12-41-20-850x411.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/TOTAL2_2024-11-28_12-41-20-768x371.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/TOTAL2_2024-11-28_12-41-20-1536x743.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/TOTAL2_2024-11-28_12-41-20-150x73.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1545px) 100vw, 1545px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Total Altcoin Market Cap. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/lsytBsUW/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>The consensus among analysts is that altcoin season will arrive, but its scale and scope remain uncertain. Institutional interest in Bitcoin has reshaped the market, reducing the direct spillover into altcoins. Retail participation, essential for smaller altcoins, has shifted focus to niche sectors like meme coins and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-traders-predict-comeback/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Solana</a>.</p>



<p>Ultimately, altcoins must innovate to attract new capital independently. Whether through unique use cases, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sui-introduces-bitcoin-staking/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">partnerships</a>, or technology breakthroughs, the path forward requires more than reliance on Bitcoin’s momentum.</p>



<p>As Ki Young Ju aptly summarized, “Bitcoin’s future growth is tied to ETFs, institutions, and governments—not retail traders. Altcoins must adapt to this new reality to thrive.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/delay-of-altcoin-season-cryptoquant/">CryptoQuant CEO Analyzes Reasons Behind Altcoin Season’s Delay</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance to List Cow Protocol (COW) and Cetus Protocol (CETUS) for Spot Trading </title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/binance-to-list-cow-and-cetus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=603247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Binance lists COW and CETUS tokens with zero fees and a "seed tag" for volatility warning, enhancing access to new crypto assets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-to-list-cow-and-cetus/">Binance to List Cow Protocol (COW) and Cetus Protocol (CETUS) for Spot Trading </a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Binance, the largest crypto exchange by trading volume, announced plans to list Cow Protocol (COW) and Cetus Protocol (CETUS)&nbsp;tokens. It will open trading for a select list of spot trading pairs.</strong></p>



<p>Of note, accessibility to these tokens for trading on Binance is subject to eligibility based on the user&#8217;s country or region of residence.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-binance-new-listings-cow-and-cetus"><strong>Binance New Listings: COW and CETUS</strong></h2>



<p>Traders will be able to trade COW and CETUS against USDT starting Wednesday, November 6, at 12:00 UTC. Before then, however, COW and CETUS holders can already deposit the token in preparation for trading, with withdrawals available starting Thursday.</p>



<p>Binance&#8217;s new listings, COW and CETUS, will be at zero fees, meaning users can trade the token on the platform without incurring any trading fees. This is a promotional strategy among exchanges, often used to attract more users.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/binance-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Binance Review 2024: Is It the Right Crypto Exchange for You?</a></strong></p>



<p>Nevertheless, the exchange articulated that it would apply a seed tag. This is a special identifier that helps distinguish COW and CETUS from other tokens. It is a precaution given the relative newness of the new Binance listings in the market, making them subject to higher-than-normal risk and, therefore, volatility.</p>



<p>COW is the native token for Cow Protocol, a decentralized finance (DeFi) solution using batch auctions, P2P trades, and solvers to find the best possible exchange rates for users. Meanwhile, CETUS powers the Cetus Protocol, a MOVE-based liquidity protocol enabling swap, earn, and build on Layer-1 blockchain, Sui.</p>



<p>GeckoTerminal shows COW and CETUS tokens are already soaring. In a typical “buy the rumor” situation, they are up between 55% and 80%.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="2120" height="1174" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Снимок-экрана-2024-11-06-в-14.18.48.png" alt="" class="wp-image-603445" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Снимок-экрана-2024-11-06-в-14.18.48.png 2120w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Снимок-экрана-2024-11-06-в-14.18.48-360x199.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Снимок-экрана-2024-11-06-в-14.18.48-850x471.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Снимок-экрана-2024-11-06-в-14.18.48-768x425.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Снимок-экрана-2024-11-06-в-14.18.48-1536x851.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Снимок-экрана-2024-11-06-в-14.18.48-2048x1134.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Снимок-экрана-2024-11-06-в-14.18.48-150x83.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2120px) 100vw, 2120px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">COW/USD Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.geckoterminal.com/eth/pools/0xfcfdfc98062d13a11cec48c44e4613eb26a34293" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GeckoTerminal</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>The listing of COW and CETUS tokens on Binance highlights the exchange&#8217;s commitment to supporting and promoting blockchain projects. By providing a platform for these tokens to reach a wider audience, Binance is facilitating greater adoption and growth within the cryptocurrency ecosystem.</p>



<p>The move is part of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ponke-binance-listing-price-impact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Binance&#8217;s continuous efforts to diversify its offerings</a>. It also progressively provides its users with access to novel projects in the blockchain space. Token holders will benefit from increased liquidity. <br><br>Traders and investors can expect a surge in trading activity and interest following the listing of Cow Protocol and Cetus Protocol tokens on Binance. Nevertheless, as they gear up to start trading COW and CETUS, it is important to exercise caution. Market participants must conduct thorough research and practice proper risk management strategies.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/how-to-trade-binance-futures-crypto/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How To Trade Crypto on Binance Futures: Everything You Need To Know</a></strong></p>



<p>The volatile nature of the cryptocurrency market means that prices can fluctuate rapidly. Traders should brace for sudden price swings.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-to-list-cow-and-cetus/">Binance to List Cow Protocol (COW) and Cetus Protocol (CETUS) for Spot Trading </a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/BIC_Binance_exchange-covers-neutral.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/BIC_Binance_exchange-covers-neutral.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance Announces Delisting for 4 Altcoins: Here&#8217;s What You Need to Know</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/binance-announces-delisting-for-4-altcoins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 07:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Trading News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=594137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Binance will delist four altcoin trading pairs on November 6, 2024, urging users to review their trading and withdrawal plans.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-announces-delisting-for-4-altcoins/">Binance Announces Delisting for 4 Altcoins: Here&#8217;s What You Need to Know</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Binance, one of the world’s largest crypto exchanges, has declared the delisting of four altcoin’s spot trading pairs.</strong></p>



<p>This action, set to take effect on November 6 at 03:00 UTC, reflects Binance’s attempts to enhance market quality.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-token-holders-on-binance-need-to-do"><strong>What Token Holders on Binance Need To Do?</strong></h2>



<p>Binance periodically evaluates the performance of its listed trading pairs to ensure they progressively meet a high level of standard and industry requirements. Based on this, it removes or delists those that fall below the bar. The exchange claims these measures protect users and uphold a high-quality trading environment amidst a changing market.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/binance-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Binance Review 2024: Is It the Right Crypto Exchange for You?</a></strong></p>



<p>Against this backdrop, the exchange will delist trading pairs for Rupiah Token (IDRT), Keep3rV1 (KP3R), Ooki Protocol (OOKI), and Unifi Protocol DAO (UNFI). Specifically:</p>



<ol class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-decimal list-inside ">
<li>USDT/IDRT</li>



<li>KP3R/USDT</li>



<li>OOKI/USDT</li>



<li>UNFI/TRY, UNFI USDT, and UNFI/BTC</li>
</ol>



<p>Noteworthy, Binance will remove all trade orders after trading ceases in each respective trading pair. This means that token holders would no longer be able to view the valuation of these tokens in their wallet after delisting.</p>



<p>Amidst these Binance delistings, the exchange has given a window for token holders, noting that deposits after November 7,&nbsp;2024, at 03:00 (UTC) will not be credited to users’ accounts. Furthermore, withdrawals of these tokens from Binance will not be supported after February 6, 2025, at 03:00 (UTC).</p>



<p>Binance might convert the delisted tokens into stablecoins on February 7, 2025, at 03:00 UTC. <span style="margin: 0px;padding: 0px">While this is subject to</span> confirmation, the exchange committed to a separate notification before the conversion.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“A separate notification will be made before the conversion where applicable, and the stablecoins will be credited to users’ Binance accounts after the conversion,&#8221; the crypto exchange <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/binance-will-delist-idrt-kp3r-ooki-unfi-on-2024-11-06-043c8407bb904652a428573a50d07e07?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">explained</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This means users with an interest in these pairs should revise their trading strategies accordingly. Importantly, the exchange will also eliminate KP3R/USDT, OOKI/USDT, UNFI/BTC, UNFI/USDT cross, and isolated margin pairs from Margin.&nbsp;Binance advises traders to either cancel or update their automated trades to avoid potential financial losses.</p>



<p>In the immediate aftermath of this round of delisting news, the value of KP3R, OOKI, and UNFI tokens has severely dropped.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-portfolio-altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">11 Cryptos To Add To Your Portfolio Before Altcoin Season</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="2722" height="1572" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/UNFIUSDT_2024-10-23_13-28-41.png" alt="" class="wp-image-594153" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/UNFIUSDT_2024-10-23_13-28-41.png 2722w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/UNFIUSDT_2024-10-23_13-28-41-360x208.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/UNFIUSDT_2024-10-23_13-28-41-850x491.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/UNFIUSDT_2024-10-23_13-28-41-768x444.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/UNFIUSDT_2024-10-23_13-28-41-1536x887.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/UNFIUSDT_2024-10-23_13-28-41-2048x1183.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/UNFIUSDT_2024-10-23_13-28-41-150x87.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2722px) 100vw, 2722px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><br>KP3R, OOKI, and UNFI Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/0GBscQES/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>This is unsurprising, given the history of token delistings on Binance has often resulted in price&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-causes-bitcoins-volatility/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">volatility</a>, leading to substantial price drops for concerned altcoins</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-announces-delisting-for-4-altcoins/">Binance Announces Delisting for 4 Altcoins: Here&#8217;s What You Need to Know</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Bina.png" medium="image" width="688" height="390" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Bina.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HashKey Capital Is Bullish on Altcoins Amid Bitcoin’s Prevailing Boom</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/hashkey-capital-is-bullish-on-altcoins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 17:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=593624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>HashKey Capital is optimistic about altcoins, looking at the sector as a good investment opportunity given Bitcoin's continued boom. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hashkey-capital-is-bullish-on-altcoins/">HashKey Capital Is Bullish on Altcoins Amid Bitcoin’s Prevailing Boom</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>HashKey Capital remains optimistic about altcoins, taking cues from the ongoing Bitcoin boom. Their bullish stance is based on a mix of market analysis, strategic investments, and economic factors that suggest strong potential for low-cap tokens.</strong></p>



<p>At the same time, Bitcoin (BTC) continues to perform well, with the $70,000 milestone within reach. Should positive sentiment lead to capital flowing into altcoins, Ethereum and Solana are expected to be the primary beneficiaries.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-hashkey-capital-eyes-market-potential-for-altcoins"><strong>HashKey Capital Eyes Market Potential for Altcoins </strong></h2>



<p>The investment firm has articulated its bullish outlook in a recent Medium post. It <a href="https://medium.com/hashkey-capital-insights/why-we-are-bullish-on-altcoins-2d3fa773289e" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">outlined</a> the strategic rationale behind its focus on altcoins amid changing market outlook and investor sentiments. Specifically, HashKey Capital has identified a critical shift in investor behavior, citing an increasing demand for diversified portfolios that extend beyond Bitcoin and Ethereum.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-growing-institutional-interest"><strong>Growing Institutional Interest</strong></h3>



<p>The post emphasizes that the increasing institutional interest in cryptocurrencies serves as a strong catalyst for the growth of altcoins. It highlights the growing narrative around cryptocurrencies as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-680-million-bitcoin-purchase-ibit-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">major financial players and asset managers become more involved in the digital asset space</a>. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Further, institutions are looking beyond Bitcoin and Ethereum, considering altcoins as viable investment vehicles. Among them is Bitwise, which recently <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitwise-updates-xrp-etf-filing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revised its XRP ETF (exchange-traded fund) filing</a>. Others<span style="margin: 0px;padding: 0px">, like&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-launches-aave-trust/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grayscale, are pivoting their trust funds to altcoins such as Aave</a>,&nbsp;Sui, and&nbsp;</span>XRP.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/best-altcoin-exchanges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">10 Best Altcoin Exchanges In 2024</a></strong></p>



<p>According to Jupiter Zheng, HashKey Capital&#8217;s partner of liquids funds and research, professional investors are eager to explore altcoin opportunities. Due to their lower market capitalization and growth potential​, these tokens have historically provided substantial returns.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-changing-market-conditions"><strong>Changing Market Conditions</strong></h3>



<p>HashKey Capital’s optimism is also grounded in favorable market conditions. Recent trends indicate that cryptocurrency markets are stabilizing, aided by <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-price-global-liquidity/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">improved liquidity</a> and shifting macroeconomic conditions. The firm points to signs of a market bottoming out, which, coupled with the potential <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fed-rate-cuts-bitcoin-experts-bullish/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">easing of US interest rates</a>, is seen as a favorable environment for altcoin investments.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“The peaking of US interest rates combined with improved liquidity in the crypto market creates an ideal environment for investors to explore altcoins,”​ Zheng noted</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The increase in applications for spot crypto ETFs (exchange-traded funds) also reflects a growing acceptance and normalization of digital assets. For instance, Nashville-based investment firm <a href="https://beincrypto.com/canary-capital-litecoin-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Canary Capital filed for a Litecoin ETF</a>, which further enhances the investment avenue for altcoins.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-regional-regulatory-boost"><strong>Regional Regulatory Boost</strong></h2>



<p>Another key component of HashKey Capital’s bullish outlook on altcoins is the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hong-kong-allows-digital-yuan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">supportive regulatory environment</a>. Hong Kong is a key focus for the asset manager, given that it is based there. The region has made significant strides in establishing a strong framework for digital assets.</p>



<p>This has attracted institutional interest and provided a favorable atmosphere for crypto investments, with the likes of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/moca-coin-turns-heads-as-animoca-brands-explores-ipo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Animoca Brands exploring a possible IPO (initial public offering) in Hong Kong</a> or the Middle East. The regulatory clarity is expected to facilitate greater adoption of altcoins and pave the way for new projects to emerge​.</p>



<p>As HashKey navigates this regulatory playing field, its focus on altcoins aligns with the broader trend of institutional players entering the market. This influx of capital and expertise is anticipated to drive innovation and create new investment opportunities within the altcoin space​.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-diversification-strategy"><strong>Diversification Strategy</strong></h3>



<p>Nevertheless, HashKey Capital&#8217;s strategy goes beyond capitalizing on market trends. It is also about prudent risk management through diversification. The firm plans to allocate less than 50% of its funds to Bitcoin and Ethereum, allowing for greater exposure to smaller-cap cryptocurrencies. This strategic allocation aims to optimize risk-return profiles by tapping into the potential of various altcoin projects.</p>



<p>The selection criteria prioritize projects that exhibit strong fundamentals and novel approaches.&nbsp;Taken together, the asset manager&#8217;s altcoin pivot highlights an understanding of market inefficiencies. Smaller market cap-sized cryptocurrencies often experience higher volatility, but they also provide opportunities for outsized returns. By strategically investing in a range of altcoins, the crypto investment firm&nbsp;seeks to balance risk while pursuing substantial upside potential.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-portfolio-altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">11 Cryptos To Add To Your Portfolio Before Altcoin Season</a></strong>.</p>



<p>HashKey Capital’s expression of bullishness on altcoins is timely, coming along with analysts’ expectation that the colloquial “<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">alt season</a>&#8221; is near sight. As BeInCrypto reported, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-ready-start/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Altcoin Season Index has dropped to its lowest level since early September</a>, signaling a potential shift. Nevertheless, some are also <a href="https://beincrypto.com/analyst-probes-altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">skeptical about an altcoin season happening</a>, given Bitcoin&#8217;s prevailing dominance.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hashkey-capital-is-bullish-on-altcoins/">HashKey Capital Is Bullish on Altcoins Amid Bitcoin’s Prevailing Boom</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_altcoins_positive_evening_sand_desert_mountains.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_altcoins_positive_evening_sand_desert_mountains.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why These Altcoins Are Trending Today — October 21</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-trending-today-october-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victor Olanrewaju]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=592645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>KOALA AI, KLAUS, and Goatseus Maximus top the trending altcoins list, driven by meme coin hype and whale accumulation, but risks remain.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-trending-today-october-21/">Why These Altcoins Are Trending Today — October 21</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Several cryptocurrencies are experiencing a notable level of relief, with some gaining attention by entering the list of altcoins trending today. This surge could be attributed to improved investor sentiment and decreasing selling pressure.</strong></p>



<p>Using data from CoinGecko, BeInCrypto highlights the top trending altcoins, the factors driving their popularity, and what might come next. The top three trending altcoins on October 21 are KOALA AI (KOKO), KLAUS (KLAUS), and Goatseus Maximus (GOAT).</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-koala-ai-koko-nbsp">KOALA AI (KOKO)&nbsp;</h2>



<p>KOALA AI, a project that combines the humor of meme coins with the power of Artificial Intelligence (AI), tops the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-trending-today-october-18/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">list of trending altcoins</a> today. Inspired by the frog-themed meme coin Pepe (PEPE), KOALA AI is gaining traction due to the growing bullish sentiment around the AI + meme coin narrative that has been dominating the market since last week.</p>



<p>As a result, KOKO’s price has surged by 70% in the last 24 hours, currently trading at $0.0000055. According to the daily chart, the Relative Strength Index (RSI) reading has crossed the overbought level, which is usually above 70.00.</p>



<p>It is also the same with the Money Flow Index (MFI), whose reading has surpassed 80.00. While these positions imply massive buying pressure, they also indicate that profit-taking could soon begin.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-exchange-fees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Best Crypto Exchanges With the Lowest Trading Fees</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="3190" height="1802" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/koko-price-analysis-altcoins.png" alt="KOALA AI trending altcoins analysis" class="wp-image-592662" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/koko-price-analysis-altcoins.png 3190w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/koko-price-analysis-altcoins-360x203.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/koko-price-analysis-altcoins-850x480.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/koko-price-analysis-altcoins-768x434.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/koko-price-analysis-altcoins-1536x868.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/koko-price-analysis-altcoins-2048x1157.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/koko-price-analysis-altcoins-150x85.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 3190px) 100vw, 3190px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">KOALA AI Daily Price Analysis. Source: <a href="https://tradingview.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>If that happens, KOKO’s might lose its place as one of the altcoins trending today. In that case, the price could also decline to $0.0000047. However, if bulls keep up the pressure, the altcoin’s value could rise and break above $0.0000060;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading">KLAUS (KLAUS)</h2>



<p>Next on the list is KLAUS, which is also a cryptocurrency with a meme coin narrative behind it. KLAUS is a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-trending-today-october-17/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trending altcoin today</a> because its price has increased by 565% within the last seven days.</p>



<p>As of this writing, the KLAUS price is $0.040. On the one-hour chart, the altcoin faces notable overhead resistance at $0.045, which is one reason KLAUS’s price might continue to struggle in the short term.</p>



<p>Given the current technical setup, the cryptocurrency’s price is likely to drop to $0.030. But traders interested in this altcoin should watch out.&nbsp; Should KLAUS break through the overhead resistance, this prediction might be invalidated, and the token could climb to $0.056.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="3190" height="1802" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/klaus-altcoins-trending-analysis.png" alt="KLAUS altcoin trending price analysis" class="wp-image-592653" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/klaus-altcoins-trending-analysis.png 3190w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/klaus-altcoins-trending-analysis-360x203.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/klaus-altcoins-trending-analysis-850x480.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/klaus-altcoins-trending-analysis-768x434.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/klaus-altcoins-trending-analysis-1536x868.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/klaus-altcoins-trending-analysis-2048x1157.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/klaus-altcoins-trending-analysis-150x85.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 3190px) 100vw, 3190px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">KLAUS 1-Hour Price Analysis. Source: <a href="https://tradingview.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading">Goatseus Maximus (GOAT)</h2>



<p>Goatseus Maximus appears to be the frontrunner of the ongoing AI + meme coin narrative in the market. This is because it is one of the altcoins that Truth Terminal, the AI that recently <a href="https://beincrypto.com/truth-terminal-becomes-crypto-millionaire/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">became a millionaire</a>, held to reach that status.</p>



<p>However, GOAT&#8217;s price recently dropped by 50%. This happened following reports that the Truth Terminal is operated by humans, contributing to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/goat-meme-coin-fell-ai-typo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">its inclusion in the altcoins</a> trending today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite the initial drop and FUD around it, Lookonchain <a href="https://x.com/lookonchain/status/1848262510551380376" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">reported</a> that a whale accumulated another $2 million worth of GOAT.&nbsp; Currently, the same whale holds&nbsp; 21.39 million, which was acquired using $7.14 million.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-portfolio-altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">11 Cryptos To Add To Your Portfolio Before Altcoin Season</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="3190" height="1802" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/goat-altcoins-trending-price-analysis.png" alt="GOAT price analysis" class="wp-image-592650" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/goat-altcoins-trending-price-analysis.png 3190w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/goat-altcoins-trending-price-analysis-360x203.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/goat-altcoins-trending-price-analysis-850x480.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/goat-altcoins-trending-price-analysis-768x434.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/goat-altcoins-trending-price-analysis-1536x868.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/goat-altcoins-trending-price-analysis-2048x1157.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/goat-altcoins-trending-price-analysis-150x85.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 3190px) 100vw, 3190px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Goatseus Maximus 4-Hour Price Analysis. Source: <a href="https://tradingview.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView </a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Following this development, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-meme-coin-goat-attracts-crypto-whales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GOAT’s price increased</a> again and currently sits at $0.40. However, if large accumulation continues, the altcoin’s value might rally to $0.58 in the short term.</p>



<p>On the contrary, if <a href="https://x.com/lookonchain/status/1848288319425134820" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">crypto whales begin to sell</a> in large numbers like one is doing, this forecast might not come to pass. Instead, GOAT’s price might fall to $0.29.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-trending-today-october-21/">Why These Altcoins Are Trending Today — October 21</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral-3.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral-3.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Analysts Adjust Altcoin Portfolios as Bitcoin Clings to $68,000</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/crypto-analysts-adjust-altcoin-portfolios/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin (DOGE) News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=591575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Crypto analysts adjust their altcoin portfolios as Bitcoin hovers at $68,000. AI-focused and meme coins gain attention, while profit-taking strategies recommend reallocating to Bitcoin.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-analysts-adjust-altcoin-portfolios/">Crypto Analysts Adjust Altcoin Portfolios as Bitcoin Clings to $68,000</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Crypto analysts are looking at certain altcoins in a proactive attempt to position their portfolios strategically. The rebalancing comes as Bitcoin (BTC) hovers around $68,000</strong>.</p>



<p>Typically, bullish sentiment in the Bitcoin market spills over to altcoins as capital rotates to smaller tokens with smaller market capitalizations.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-analysts-identify-top-altcoins-picks-for-q4"><strong>Analysts Identify Top Altcoins Picks For Q4</strong></h2>



<p>Miles Deutscher, a popular crypto analyst, positions his portfolio with altcoins from select <span style="margin: 0px;padding: 0px">market sectors. He <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=36Juw_N1Uzg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reveals</a> a balanced blend of AI-focused projects and long-term meme coin holdings. These come as the analyst aims to capitalize on </span>the technical and fundamental strengths of the following digital assets, among others.</p>



<p>Deutscher views <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bittensor-tao-price-may-tumble/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bittensor (TAO)</a> as a leader in the AI cryptocurrency space, positioning it as his top holding for this cycle. He explains that TAO has been a high performer in his portfolio, driven by its AI infrastructure, which has garnered significant attention.</p>



<p>Another key asset in Deutscher&#8217;s portfolio is NEAR Protocol (NEAR), one of the leading <a href="https://beincrypto.com/layer-1-blockchain-scalability-solutions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Layer-1 (L1) blockchains</a> for AI. While TAO leads the AI infrastructure sector, NEAR is positioned as the primary AI L1 solution, making it integral to the broader investment thesis. Additionally, according to Deutscher, NEAR’s growing prominence in the AI space makes it a compelling addition for those looking to diversify within the AI crypto niche.</p>



<p>Finally, <span style="margin: 0px;padding: 0px">Deutscher highlights<a href="https://beincrypto.com/aethir-ecosystem-fund-cloud-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Aethir (ATH) </a>as another significant part of his portfolio among lower-cap assets. He</span> emphasizes that while AI coins have been widely discussed, the market has yet to experience a full-fledged &#8220;AI season,&#8221; meaning many of these assets remain undervalued.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/ai-cryptocurrencies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Top 9 Artificial Intelligence (AI) Cryptocurrencies in 2024</a></strong></p>



<p>In his view, Aethir has the potential for explosive growth once the AI narrative gains more momentum. For now, he advises cautious accumulation on dips, with the understanding that significant gains could be realized once AI coins become more widely adopted.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-dogecoin-for-high-risk-high-reward-plays"><strong>Dogecoin For High-Risk, High-Reward Plays</strong></h2>



<p>Deutscher also included Dogecoin (DOGE) in his altcoin strategy for Q4. The meme coin, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dogecoin-doge-price-could-correct/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">already up 25%</a>, has shown strong performance driven by speculation around Donald Trump&#8217;s potential presidential run in 2024. Additionally, crypto influencer Andrew Kang’s endorsement has further bolstered market confidence in DOGE as a viable speculative trade.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“One of the most interesting ways to express a “Trump Victory” trade would probably be owning DOGE (and other memes) Not only do you have high odds of a Doge ETF but the Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) would be making headlines every week and be pushed forward by Trump,” Kang <a href="https://x.com/Rewkang/status/1846231275847454786" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">noted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>While DOGE remains a high-risk play, Deutscher sees potential in its ability to capture market enthusiasm during periods of heightened speculation. He suggests that those looking for shorter-term gains could consider Dogecoin, though he cautions that it should not make up a large portion of an investor&#8217;s portfolio.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="769" height="562" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dddd-38.png" alt="DOGE Price Performance" class="wp-image-591581" style="aspect-ratio:1.3683274021352314;width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dddd-38.png 769w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dddd-38-360x263.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dddd-38-150x110.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 769px) 100vw, 769px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">DOGE Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/dogecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BeInCrypto</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>BeInCrypto data shows that DOGE is trading for $0.1338 as of this writing, up by almost 10% since the Friday session opened.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-taking-profits-and-rotating-back-to-bitcoin"><strong>Taking Profits and Rotating Back to Bitcoin</strong></h2>



<p>Beyond these primary plays, another popular analyst, Michaël van de Poppe, draws attention to a range of other projects. He <a href="https://youtu.be/MioAH4YSHsY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">highlights</a> the need to take profits and rotate them back to Bitcoin.</p>



<p>Michael argues that older altcoins that performed well in previous cycles may not replicate their past success. With this, he points traders and investors to altcoins in their early stages but with the potential for greater returns. </p>



<p>Advising calculated risks by focusing on emerging projects, the analyst highlights Renzo (REZ), which <a href="https://beincrypto.com/renzo-ezsol-launch-solana-liquid-restaking-token-lrt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recently entered the Solana ecosystem</a>. Other mentions include Omni Network (OMNI) and Rocket Pool (RPL), among others.</p>



<p>Michael van de Poppe recommends monitoring for upward trends and taking profits when an altcoin’s price approaches its previous high. Once profits are taken, he advises reallocating into Bitcoin and Ethereum or <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-a-stablecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stablecoins</a>, depending on the market’s condition. This strategy, according to Michael, allows investors to protect gains while preparing for future corrections.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/best-exchange-trade-altcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">12 Best Altcoin Exchanges for Crypto Trading in October 2024</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="The Best Altcoin Trading Strategy This Bull Cycle!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MioAH4YSHsY?feature=oembed&#038;enablejsapi=1&#038;origin=https://beincrypto.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>The analyst also encourages an overreaching strategy, compounding returns through newer altcoins while gradually moving profits into safer, more established assets like Bitcoin and Ethereum. This approach, he says, positions investors to maximize returns while managing risks in a volatile market.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-analysts-adjust-altcoin-portfolios/">Crypto Analysts Adjust Altcoin Portfolios as Bitcoin Clings to $68,000</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Analyst Reveals 4 Altcoins for Up to 10X Gains</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/deutscher-reveals-top-altcoins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 14:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=589814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Renowned analyst Miles Deutscher's top four altcoin picks—SUPER, TAO, RNDR, and OM—tap into hot trends in gaming, AI, and real-world asset tokenization.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/deutscher-reveals-top-altcoins/">Crypto Analyst Reveals 4 Altcoins for Up to 10X Gains</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>As Bitcoin continues to show strength, analysts are diverting their attention to altcoins with hot narratives — GameFi, AI, DePIN, and RWA.</strong></p>



<p>Hence, renowned crypto analyst Miles Deutscher unveiled his top four altcoin picks, naming potential high-yield investments riding on these narratives.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-superverse-super-riding-the-gaming-wave"><strong>SuperVerse (SUPER): Riding the Gaming Wave</strong></h2>



<p>The analyst ranks SUPER, a gaming token, at the top of his list, calling it a &#8220;meme&#8221; due to its strong community support. However, he stressed that SUPER also offers real utility within the gaming economy. He noted that the combination of cultural appeal and practical use is often key to determining which crypto projects succeed.</p>



<p>SUPER has seen immense growth amid the rise of play-to-earn models and the integration of NFTs (<a href="https://beincrypto.com/nfts-are-considered-dead/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">non-fungible tokens</a>). &nbsp;The token has surged 70% since Deutscher&#8217;s September 21 call, and he believes it has even more room for growth. He attributes the success to the powerful influence of belief and community support.</p>



<p>For gaming investors, Deutscher sees SUPER as a key altcoin to stack, with future gains expected as the market recognizes its potential.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-bittensor-tao-leading-the-ai-narrative">Bittensor (TAO): Leading the AI Narrative</h2>



<p>TAO is another top pick, benefiting from the ongoing AI narrative. AI&#8217;s potential to revolutionize multiple industries, along with crypto’s integration into that revolution, makes <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bittensor-golden-cross/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bittensor</a> a critical player in the space.</p>



<p>Deutscher notes that TAO has garnered attention both within and outside the crypto space, even receiving a boost from Elon Musk’s mention on X (formerly Twitter). He highlights TAO’s long-term potential due to its central role in AI infrastructure.</p>



<p>According to the analyst, TAO has consistently provided buying opportunities through minor pullbacks, making it a solid choice for investors eyeing the AI sector.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="738" height="547" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dddd-28.png" alt="TAO Price Performance" class="wp-image-589826" style="aspect-ratio:1.3491773308957953;width:1020px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dddd-28.png 738w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dddd-28-360x267.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dddd-28-150x111.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 738px) 100vw, 738px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">TAO Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/bittensor/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BeInCrypto</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>While the token has already seen significant gains, Deutscher advises buying during dips. At the time of writing, TAO is trading at $609.16. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-mantra-om-betting-on-rwa">Mantra (OM): Betting on RWA</h2>



<p>Mantra <a href="https://beincrypto.com/rwa-tokenization-democratize-wealth/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">positions itself at the intersection of DeFi and real-world assets (RWA)</a>. Deutscher bets on its unique position in the RWA space, which, in his opinion, makes it an attractive long-term hold. The niche promises immense growth potential in the coming years.</p>



<p>RWA tokenization — the process of converting physical assets like real estate, bonds, and commodities into digital tokens on the blockchain — is gaining momentum. High-profile figures, including <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-larry-fink-bitcoin-ethereum-tokenization/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlackRock&#8217;s Larry Fink</a>, continue to emphasize its growing significance.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“We have the technology to tokenize today. If you have a tokenized&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/top10-must-have-cryptocurrency-security-tips/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">security</a>&nbsp;and identity, the moment you buy or sell an instrument on a general ledger, that is all created together. You want to talk about issues around money laundering. This eliminates all corruption by having a tokenized system,” Fink explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Mantra&#8217;s ability to ride this wave, coupled with its current technical setup, makes it a strong contender for long-term growth. Mantra’s <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/mantra-dao/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OM token price</a> has already delivered impressive returns, with a 2X to 3X increase since Deutscher&#8217;s initial recommendation. Despite its recent price surge, Deutscher expects further growth and suggests buying during potential retracements.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-render-rndr-a-depin-player-with-technical-strength">Render (RNDR): A DePIN Player with Technical Strength</h2>



<p>RNDR rounds out the analyst’s top four picks. Deutscher picks Render as a top decentralized physical infrastructure network (<a href="https://beincrypto.com/depin-news-grass-appears-on-okx-pre-market/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DePIN</a>) play. Render provides decentralized GPU computing power, which has a variety of use cases, especially in AI and high-performance computing.</p>



<p>While there are other promising projects in the sector, including Aethir (<a href="https://beincrypto.com/arthur-hayes-sells-pendle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ATH</a>), Deutscher finds Render particularly appealing for both short-term trading and long-term holding. &nbsp;Its current <a href="https://beincrypto.com/render-rndr-price-struggles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">price action</a> and technical setup indicate that it could see significant gains soon, making it a strong altcoin to watch. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="4 Best Crypto Altcoins To Buy Now For 10x Gains!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hlB0r5-Xbpo?feature=oembed&#038;enablejsapi=1&#038;origin=https://beincrypto.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Miles Deutscher’s top four altcoin picks—SUPER, TAO, Render, and Mantra—represent broader crypto trends capable of dominating the market. Each of these tokens stands at the forefront of narratives shaping the future of crypto.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/best-exchange-trade-altcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">12 Best Altcoin Exchanges for Crypto Trading in October 2024</a></strong></p>



<p>Investors seeking opportunities in the altcoin space may consider monitoring these four projects, balancing short-term technical analysis with long-term market trends. However, traders must always conduct their own research.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/deutscher-reveals-top-altcoins/">Crypto Analyst Reveals 4 Altcoins for Up to 10X Gains</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/bic_Altcoins-covers_neutral_3.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/bic_Altcoins-covers_neutral_3.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance May Soon Delist These 5 Altcoins: Everything You Need to Know</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/binance-may-delist-five-altcoins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 07:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=581728</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Binance may delist five altcoins under scrutiny for meeting listing criteria, causing notable price drops in the market.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-may-delist-five-altcoins/">Binance May Soon Delist These 5 Altcoins: Everything You Need to Know</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Binance, the world’s largest crypto exchange, has flagged five altcoins for potential delisting. </strong></p>



<p>This decision comes as the exchange added Bluzelle (BLZ), CLV (CLV), SelfKey (KEY), Prosper (PROS), and VITE (VITE) to its Monitoring Tag list, indicating increased scrutiny due to heightened volatility and risks.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-altcoins-crash-due-to-risks-of-binance-delisting">Altcoins Crash Due to Risks of Binance Delisting </h2>



<p>The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-raises-flags-11-altcoins-risk-future-delistings/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monitoring Tag</a> is Binance’s method of singling out tokens that might not meet its stringent listing criteria anymore. The review criteria are thorough, assessing factors from the team’s commitment to the project, the quality and level of development activity, to the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hamster-kombat-volume-after-hmstr-airdrop/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trading volume</a> and liquidity. It also examines the stability and safety of the network and responsiveness to Binance’s periodic due diligence requests.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Keep in mind that tokens with the Monitoring Tag are at risk of no longer meeting our listing criteria and being delisted from the platform,” Binance <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/binance-will-extend-the-monitoring-tag-to-include-blz-clv-key-pros-vite-and-remove-the-seed-tag-for-pendle-sei-on-2024-10-03-2178333b0324406088737cf07436ba43?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">warned</a>. </p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/binance-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Binance Review 2024: Is It the Right Crypto Exchange for You?</a></strong></p>



<p>Consequently, this alert triggered a sharp decline in the prices of these altcoins. VITE saw the most substantial impact, plummeting nearly 25%. PROS and CLV followed with drops of 15.74% and 15.22%, respectively.</p>



<p>Despite the market’s downturn, KEY and BLZ demonstrated some resilience. Initially, KEY’s value fell by 9%, but it later recovered, now showing a 7.35% decrease. <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bluzelle-price-risk-whales-prepare-sell/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BLZ also experienced a swift drop</a> of 12%, yet it has largely regained its footing, now down by only 4.54%.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="2734" height="1572" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/VITEUSDT_2024-10-03_12-58-05.png" alt="
BLZ, CLV, KEY, PROS, and VITE Price Performance" class="wp-image-581806" style="aspect-ratio:1.738241308793456;width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/VITEUSDT_2024-10-03_12-58-05.png 2734w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/VITEUSDT_2024-10-03_12-58-05-360x207.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/VITEUSDT_2024-10-03_12-58-05-850x489.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/VITEUSDT_2024-10-03_12-58-05-768x442.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/VITEUSDT_2024-10-03_12-58-05-1536x883.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/VITEUSDT_2024-10-03_12-58-05-2048x1178.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/VITEUSDT_2024-10-03_12-58-05-150x86.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2734px) 100vw, 2734px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">BLZ, CLV, KEY, PROS, and VITE Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/uKXmFovo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Furthermore, in a contrasting decision, Binance has removed the Seed Tag from two altcoins, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/arthur-hayes-sells-pendle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pendle (PENDLE)</a> and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sei-price-promises-another-21-hike/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sei (SEI)</a>. This adjustment suggests these tokens have stabilized and are now considered less risky. The Seed Tag typically marks newer projects that inherently carry greater volatility and risks.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-portfolio-altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">11 Cryptos To Add To Your Portfolio Before Altcoin Season</a></strong></p>



<p>For those engaging with tokens under either the Monitoring Tag or Seed Tag, Binance requires users to pass specific quizzes every 90 days. These quizzes aim to ensure that traders are fully aware of the risks involved.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-may-delist-five-altcoins/">Binance May Soon Delist These 5 Altcoins: Everything You Need to Know</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/bic_warning_crypto_5-covers.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/bic_warning_crypto_5-covers.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Market Dips: Analysts Share Strategies For Upcoming Altcoin Season</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-strategies-buy-dip/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=581175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Despite market turbulence, crypto experts predict an altcoin season. Analysts recommend meme coins, AI tokens, and resilient assets like Fantom.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-strategies-buy-dip/">Crypto Market Dips: Analysts Share Strategies For Upcoming Altcoin Season</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Despite its historical bullishness, October&#8217;s beginning has been anything but predictable. Traditionally dubbed &#8220;Uptober&#8221; by crypto enthusiasts for its typically strong performance, this month has faced substantial disruptions. </strong></p>



<p>These disturbances stem from escalating geopolitical tensions between Israel and Iran, which intensified dramatically on October 1 with a significant missile attack—the second incident this year. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-analysts-believe-altcoin-season-is-closer">Analysts Believe Altcoin Season Is Closer</h2>



<p>This geopolitical strife has injected uncertainty into global markets, impacting cryptocurrencies with over <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-crashes-crypto-market-liquidations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$500 million in liquidations</a>. Nevertheless, some experts view these disruptions as just hiccups preceding an <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-investor-positions-for-possible-altseason/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">altcoin season</a>. </p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Altcoin season is not going anywhere. The market is doing a shakeout. People are being tested. This is just like every other test. You need to pass,&#8221; pseudonymous analyst Altcoin Buzz <a href="https://x.com/Altcoinbuzzio/status/1841384740194320601" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-portfolio-altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">11 Cryptos To Add To Your Portfolio Before Altcoin Season</a></strong></p>



<p>In response to the market downturn, prominent <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-analyst-meme-coins-trade-plan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crypto analyst Miles Deutscher</a> has outlined strategies for opportunistic buying during the dip. According to Deutscher, the key is focusing on previous leaders. </p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s actually quite simple because we just had a sample size from the market. The market gave us information on the old coins that pumped when things were really bullish last week, so what you want to do is pick the leaders during the most recent rally,&#8221; he explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Deutscher believes that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/5-meme-coins-to-watch-in-october/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">meme coins</a> and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bittensor-tao-soars-ai-tokens-outshine/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI tokens</a> have been at the forefront of the market for the last two weeks. Hence, he expects that when the market rebounds from this dip, these sectors might become the strongest performers once again.</p>



<p>Specifically, Deutscher mentioned <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dogwifhat-wif-price-could-decline/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dogwifhat (WIF)</a>, Pepe (PEPE), <a href="https://beincrypto.com/popcat-price-uptrend-momentum-fading/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Popcat (POPCAT)</a> and Mog Coin (MOG). He also pointed to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fantom-ftm-price-prediction-october/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fantom (FTM)</a>, which showed remarkable resilience during the current market dip. Despite this, Deutscher continues to maintain a position in stablecoins as a hedge against potential further downturns.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;The real alpha here is to make sure your watchlist is pre-prepared based on relative strength. If the market drops further, you&#8217;ll know exactly what to buy, and you&#8217;ll be mentally prepared rather than panicking and derisking,&#8221; Deutscher stated.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He recommends using price aggregator platforms to monitor daily top performers, which are likely to lead once the market uptrend resumes.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/top-meme-coins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">7 Hot Meme Coins and Altcoins that are Trending in 2024</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="It Was All A Trap.. [Do This To Protect Your Crypto Portfolio NOW!]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uGCbStO-HQw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Other analysts also echo the sentiment that the altcoin season is just around the corner. </p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Altcoin season is closer than ever before. Uptober is still Uptober, despite the recent Middle East confrontations. I am starting to swap more Solana (SOL) and Ethereum (ETH) into memes and promising alts that I expect to make 5-10x returns,&#8221; crypto researcher 0xFinish <a href="https://x.com/0xFinish/status/1841432387177025789" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">noted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Indeed, by preparing a strategic watchlist and understanding the relative strengths of different altcoins, investors can effectively capitalize on potential market rebounds. As always, vigilance and preparedness are key to leveraging opportunities during periods of volatility.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-strategies-buy-dip/">Crypto Market Dips: Analysts Share Strategies For Upcoming Altcoin Season</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/bic_Altcoins-covers_neutral_2.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/bic_Altcoins-covers_neutral_2.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Investor Positions for Possible Altcoin Season with These 6 Tokens</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/crypto-investor-positions-for-possible-altseason/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=572547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Analysts predict a 2024 altcoin season, fueled by Bitcoin's rise and the Fed’s rate cut. Key tokens like SUI and FTM are positioned for growth.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-investor-positions-for-possible-altseason/">Crypto Investor Positions for Possible Altcoin Season with These 6 Tokens</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Crypto investors and analysts support that the 2024 altcoin season may have just started, drawing signals from multiple fundamentals, including Bitcoin&#8217;s (BTC) sustained foray above $63,000.</strong></p>



<p>The optimism comes after the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) decided a 50 basis points interest rate cut in September, suggesting the US economy is in a good place.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-crypto-banter-founder-highlights-tokens-primed-for-altcoins"><strong>Crypto Banter Founder Highlights Tokens Primed for Altcoins</strong></h2>



<p>Crypto Banter, a popular YouTube channel with over 1.08 million subscribers, says the 2024 altcoin season is beginning. Its founder, Ran Neuner, cites the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fomc-interest-rate-cut-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Federal Reserve’s (Fed) interest cut on Wednesday</a>, increasing global liquidity and the all-time high seen in the <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MMMFFAQ027S" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">money market funds</a>. With this, he lists six tokens that are best positioned to rally if the altcoin season takes off.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sui"><strong>SUI</strong></h3>



<p>The analyst starts by highlighting Sui (SUI) as a standout token, noting its rising prominence in the market, even <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sui-solana-killer-experts-reveal-insights/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posing a threat to Solana</a> (SOL). SUI has been making headlines with major partnerships, including <a href="https://beincrypto.com/circle-usdc-stablecoin-sui-soneium-blockchains/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Circle’s USDC integration</a>. Grayscale also recently <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sui-trust-launch-propels-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launched a Sui Trust</a>, which has driven a significant increase in both price and trading volume.</p>



<p>Ran Neuner believes these strong fundamentals position SUI for success in the short term, especially if an altcoin season unfolds.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ftm"><strong>FTM</strong></h3>



<p>The analyst also highlights Fantom (FTM) as a promising altcoin, noting its strong price performance. FTM has gained attention after recent internal developments, including the rebrand to Sonic Labs in August.</p>



<p>The rebrand has sparked <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fantom-sonic-foundation-labs-10-million-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">renewed investor interest</a>, positioning Fantom for further growth. Sonic Labs is building on this momentum with the launch of Sonic Gateway, a decentralized bridge that enables secure ERC-20 token transfers between Ethereum and Sonic.</p>



<p>This development has provided a boost for FTM, which has risen by 10% since the Thursday session began, trading at $0.33, according to BeInCrypto data.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-imx"><strong>IMX</strong></h3>



<p>ImmutableX (IMX) is also on Crypto Banter’s list of altcoins poised to rally on a possible alt season. The gaming token has broken above a falling wedge pattern, effectively confirming a reversal. Based on this breakout, analysts <a href="https://x.com/ZAYKCharts/status/1836771087738380332" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">expect</a> a bullish wave.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What Is Altcoin Season? A Comprehensive Guide</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1623" height="679" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/IMXUSDT_2024-09-19_17-51-54.png" alt="IMX Price Performance" class="wp-image-572550" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/IMXUSDT_2024-09-19_17-51-54.png 1623w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/IMXUSDT_2024-09-19_17-51-54-360x151.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/IMXUSDT_2024-09-19_17-51-54-850x356.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/IMXUSDT_2024-09-19_17-51-54-768x321.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/IMXUSDT_2024-09-19_17-51-54-1536x643.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/IMXUSDT_2024-09-19_17-51-54-150x63.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1623px) 100vw, 1623px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">IMX/USDT 2-day chart, Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/WB4xl6ch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a> </figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-aero"><strong>AERO</strong></h3>



<p>The portfolio rebalancing also considers Aerodrome (AERO), as the central trading and liquidity marketplace continues to thrive on Base L2. The underlying fundamental for AERO is Aerodrome&#8217;s MetaDEX model, which combines the best aspects of previous decentralized exchange market leaders.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;When we assess Aerodrome’s implied outcomes through a model, it&#8217;s evident that token inflation, in itself, is not inherently bad. Instead, emissions are just one input into an economic model—a cost that can be managed and overcome,” a DeFi researcher <a href="https://x.com/defi_monk/status/1836463396243542061" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">echoed</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sol">SOL</h3>



<p>If the assumption proves accurate, Solana (SOL) may be gearing up for a strong rally, given its history of delivering impressive gains during altcoin market surges. Solana has often outperformed when broader altcoin momentum picks up, making it a key player to watch.</p>



<p>Currently, SOL is trading at $141.53, marking a 10% increase in the last 24 hours, according to BeInCrypto data.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-om"><strong>OM</strong></h3>



<p>MANTRA (OM) earns a spot on the analyst’s list due to the upcoming <a href="https://t.co/DcU8Rw4sNC" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">launch of its mainnet</a> in October. This event is expected to be a major milestone for the project, as it will bring real-world assets (RWA) on-chain. The mainnet launch will be a crucial step in integrating traditional finance (TradFi) into the blockchain ecosystem, creating new opportunities for MANTRA&#8217;s growth.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/how-to-invest-rwa-crypto/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How To Invest in Real-World Crypto Assets (RWA)?</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="The BIGGEST Altseason EVER Just Started! [WHAT I&#039;m Buying!]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kuloDzDpp8M?feature=oembed&#038;enablejsapi=1&#038;origin=https://beincrypto.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Ran Neuner also highlighted several other tokens that could see strong rallies, including Arweave (ARV), THORChain (RUNE), Render (RNDR), Crown by Third Time Games (CROWN), and SuperVerse (SUPER). These tokens have posted steady, conservative gains despite recent market uncertainty, positioning them for larger increases if an altcoin season takes off.</p>



<p>However, Neuner advises investors to keep an eye on the Bank of Japan’s (BOJ) CPI and interest rate decision on Friday. He warns that if the BOJ raises rates, it could disrupt the current rally, potentially leading to a market reversal. On the other hand, if the BOJ cuts interest rates, it could reinforce the ongoing upward momentum.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote">
<p>“Don’t get overconfident. We need good CPI out of Japan tomorrow and for BOJ not to raise rates on Friday. September still has some potential liquidity drains so don’t lever up to the gills, just 8 more days until it is really up only,” GamesMasterFlex <a href="https://x.com/GamesMasterFlex/status/1836611533905756525" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-investor-positions-for-possible-altseason/">Crypto Investor Positions for Possible Altcoin Season with These 6 Tokens</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_altcoins_neutral.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_altcoins_neutral.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Airdrops in the TON Ecosystem Happening This Fall</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/top-airdrops-ton-ecosystem-fall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ali Martinez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 09:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Airdrop News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=570419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The TON ecosystem exploded in 2024 with Telegram-based mini-apps like Catizen and Hamster Kombat. Anticipated airdrops this fall include CATI, HMSTR, and more.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/top-airdrops-ton-ecosystem-fall/">Top Airdrops in the TON Ecosystem Happening This Fall</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Since the start of 2024, the metrics of The Open Network (TON) ecosystem have skyrocketed by hundreds or even thousands of percent. This unprecedented growth was driven by Telegram, specifically by mini-apps in the messenger that are built on TON.</strong></p>



<p>Here are the most anticipated airdrops this fall in the TON network.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-catizen"><strong>Catizen</strong></h2>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc ">
<li><strong>When</strong>: September 24</li>



<li><strong>Amount</strong>: 430 million CATI</li>
</ul>



<p>Catizen is a project in the tap-to-earn segment, operating as a mini-app in Telegram. Since its launch, the game has attracted over 34 million users and generated $26 million in in-game purchases.</p>



<p>The Catizen team has planned <a href="https://beincrypto.com/atizen-airdrop-get-cati-tokens/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the launch of the CATI token</a> on September 24. It’s still unclear whether the airdrop will happen on the same day. Several cryptocurrency exchanges, including OKX, Bybit, Bitget, KuCoin, and HashKey Global, have already announced the listing of the CATI coin.</p>



<p>According to the project’s whitepaper, the total supply of CATI will be 1 billion tokens, with approximately 43% allocated for community rewards.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-hamster-kombat"><strong>Hamster Kombat</strong></h2>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc ">
<li><strong>When</strong>: September 26</li>



<li><strong>Amount</strong>: 60% of the total (unknown) supply of HMSTR</li>
</ul>



<p>One of the most anticipated events of recent months is the launch of the HMSTR token from Hamster Kombat. This extremely popular &#8220;tap game&#8221; has become a phenomenon, with over 150 million players.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hamster-kombat-tge-airdrop-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hamster Kombat Token Generation Event (TGE)</a> will take place on September 26. The total supply of HMSTR is still unknown, but 60% of it is reserved for the hamster community.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ton-airdrop-september-full-details/">3 Upcoming TON Blockchain Airdrops For The Month</a></strong></p>



<p>The creators of this clicker game have previously outlined the conditions necessary to participate in the airdrop, which will also determine the size of the reward.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-cats"><strong>Cats</strong></h2>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc ">
<li><strong>When</strong>: Late September</li>



<li><strong>Amount</strong>: Unknown</li>
</ul>



<p>Cats is a near-copy of the popular mini-app DOGS, which recently launched its token of the same name. Similar to the original, Cats awards points based on the user’s Telegram account age and their subscription to Telegram Premium.</p>



<p>CATS tokens can also be earned by completing various tasks, such as subscribing to the project&#8217;s social media or inviting friends. The Cats Telegram channel already has over 12 million subscribers.</p>



<p>In late August, Bitget opened the pre-market for CATS tokens. Meanwhile, OKX announced a joint initiative with Cats, distributing $30,000 among users who complete specific tasks.</p>



<p>The CATS listing is expected in the second half of the month.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-major-of-telegram"><strong>Major of Telegram</strong></h2>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc ">
<li><strong>When</strong>: October 1</li>



<li><strong>Amount</strong>: 400 million MAJOR</li>
</ul>



<p>Major is a Telegram game launched in early July of this year. The project is a competition for rankings—players must become “the best of the best.” Popularity in the app is measured by stars, which can be earned through Telegram Stars.</p>



<p>According to the developers, Major attracted 4.5 million players in just three days. The current number of users exceeds 30 million. The project is partnering with Catizen and BingX.</p>



<p>The MAJOR token is set to launch on October 1. The total supply will be 1 billion tokens, with 40% allocated to the community. The token’s pre-market is already open on Bitget.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-ton-station"><strong>TON Station</strong></h2>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc ">
<li><strong>When</strong>: October 6</li>



<li><strong>Amount</strong>: Unknown</li>
</ul>



<p>TON Station is a platform that combines Web2 and Web3 functionalities. Users can earn passive income by completing daily tasks and participating in various game activities. The integration of the SOON token creates a unique economic model, allowing players to influence the platform&#8217;s development.</p>



<p>The project’s partners include Binance Smart Chain (BSC), Linea, Polygon, OKX, and Blum.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/upcoming-airdrops/">Best Upcoming Airdrops in 2024</a></strong></p>



<p>Farming of SOON coins on the TON Station app will end on October 4, followed by the token’s listing on crypto exchanges. The tokenomics of the project have not yet been released.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-memefi"><strong>MemeFi</strong></h2>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc ">
<li><strong>When</strong>: October 9</li>



<li><strong>Amount</strong>: 9 billion MEMEFI</li>
</ul>



<p>MemeFi is a gaming platform on Telegram that offers users the opportunity to earn cryptocurrency. Digital assets can be earned by participating in battles and collecting memes. The game combines elements of a clicker and a collection game.</p>



<p>According to the developers, more than 45 million players have already joined MemeFi.</p>



<p>The launch of the MEMEFI token is scheduled for October 9. The project team has noted that the token will be listed on several major centralized exchanges (CEX), but specific names have not been disclosed.</p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://whitepaper.memefi.club/tokenomics/usdmemefi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">tokenomics</a> of MemeFi, the total supply will be 10 billion tokens, with 90% allocated to the community. The remaining funds will be distributed among early investors and partners, as well as used for liquidity.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-x-empire"><strong>X Empire</strong></h2>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc ">
<li><strong>When</strong>: October 15</li>



<li><strong>Amount</strong>: Unknown</li>
</ul>



<p>X Empire is a clicker game on Telegram similar in mechanics to Hamster Kombat. However, instead of a hamster, players &#8220;tap&#8221; Elon Musk to level him up and increase their hourly earnings.</p>



<p>In just two months, X Empire has attracted over 30 million players.</p>



<p>The mining phase of in-game coins will end on September 30, with the token listing of XEMP <a href="https://x.com/xempiregame/status/1832069177747907019" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">scheduled</a> for October 15. The project has yet to share the tokenomics.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/top-airdrops-ton-ecosystem-fall/">Top Airdrops in the TON Ecosystem Happening This Fall</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/bic_Airdrop_4-covers_bullish.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/bic_Airdrop_4-covers_bullish.jpg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
